<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
You may obtain a copy of the License at

http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
limitations under the License.








most of this page got split.
-->

<!DOCTYPE document
[
<!ENTITY root-path   '..'> <!-- The path to the incubator root -->
]>

<document>
  <properties>
    <atom url="http://mail-archives.apache.org/mod_mbox/incubator-general/?format=atom">general@incubator.apache.org Archives</atom>
    <title>Projects</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section id="Incubating+Project+and+Mentor+Guides">
      <title>Mentor Guide</title>
      <p>This document targets any Incubating Project member, but
         especially Mentors, who have to ensure that some things get done.
         For a general description of the role of a mentor on an incubating 
         project see the
        <a href="/incubation/Roles_and_Responsibilities.html#Mentor">Roles and Responsibilities
</a>document. 
     </p><p>
    This guide is a descriptive and at times
discursive document. It describes established practices. 
It is informational not normative. Policy is laid down in the
<a href="/incubation/Incubation_Policy.html">Incubation Policy</a>.
      </p>
      <section id='TOC'><title>Contents</title><toc/></section>
      </section>
      <section id="Overview">
        <title>Overview</title>
        <p>
          After the Podling has been accepted by the Incubator PMC, one of the mentors 
          <a href="/incubation/Incubation_Policy.html#Setting+Up+a+New+Podling">sets up</a>
          the Podling; <em>i.e.</em> adds the podling metadata, creates the initial Podling status page, and 
          either creates or requests that 
          other resources (mail lists, subversion, bug tracker, <em>etc.</em>) 
          be created.
        </p>
      </section>
      <section id="Sending+in+an+Incubation+Report">
        <title>Add to Incubation Summary file</title>
        <p>
          Add the podling to the podling summary file in
          the "incubator" SVN at <code>content/podlings.xml</code>
          (e.g. copy the entry from another podling that also has status="current")
          and see <a href="website.html">instructions</a>.
        </p>
        <p>
          Please do this step ASAP after Acceptance. Other setup procedures utilize
          this metadata.
        </p>
        <p>
          Add a 'reporting' tag (after 'description') with the attribute 'monthly="true"' 
          and the appropriate "group" attribute, based on the month in which  the podling
          entered incubation (1 for January, April, July, October, 2 for February, May, 
          August, November or 3 for March, June, September, December). The text content 
          of the 'reporting' tag must contain the initial list of reporting months, 
          starting with the month after the podling entered incubation. For example:
          <code>&lt;reporting group="2" monthly="true"&gt;June, July, August&lt;/reporting&gt;</code> 
          Once the first three reports are complete, the monthly attribute should be removed
          and the list of months removed as well.
        </p>
        <p>
          The first report might be
          very short. However it is better that the Incubator PMC can help to
          guide through the early setup stages.
          For more details see the
          <a href="ppmc.html#Incubator+ASF+Board+Reports">PPMC Guide</a>.
        </p>
      </section>
      <section id="Initialize+Podling+Status+Page">
        <title>Initialize Podling Status Page</title>
      <p>
      A mentor needs to
      <a href="website.html#Edit+your+project+status+page">create the
      web page</a> that will track the project's status.
      A mentor will also need to update it until 
      <a href="ppmc.html#Project+Status+Updates">others in the
      the project's PPMC can update it</a>.
      </p><p>
      The status
      page is the incubator's record of the progress made.
      It MUST be kept update to date during incubation.
      Some of the information is available from the proposal.
      As the startup process continues and resources are
      created the status SHOULD be updated. 
      </p><p>
      The template contains lists of actions which may be needed
      to start up a podling. All those which do not apply should 
      be deleted.
      </p><p>
      The status page is a useful aid to workflow. Volunteers
      can use it to sign up to the various tasks and monitor their 
      progress. Once the mailing lists are set up and prospective
      committers subscribe then these may be used for discussion.
      </p>
      </section>
	    <section id='request-required-resources'><title>Request Required Resources</title>
	      <p>
	      The proposal should include a list of required resources. All of these will 
	      require active set up. Some are created by infrastructure after an appropriate
	      request, others can be set up by any IPMC members (typically mentors).
	      </p><p>
	      Mailing lists should be created first. Other resources typically
	      post information to these lists.
	      </p>
	      <section id='request-mailing-lists'><title>Request Mailing Lists</title>
	      <p>
	      Apache mailing lists require volunteer moderators. New moderators can be 
	      <a href='http://www.apache.org/dev/committers.html#mailing-list-moderators'>changed later</a> 
	      but at least one volunteer is required before the mailing lists can be set up. 
	      Moderation is a reasonably 
	      <a href='http://www.apache.org/dev/committers.html#mail-moderate'>easy task</a>
	      though moderators may want to set up 
	      <a href='http://spamassassin.apache.org/'>spam filtering</a>.
	      Having at least three moderators is recommended to spread the load.
	      </p><p>
	      The proposal should contain the rest of the information that needs to be collected
	      before the mailing lists can be requested. Incubator is the responsible top level project.
	      So the domain <code>MUST</code> be <code>incubator.apache.org</code>.
	      For example:
	      </p>
	      <ul>
	      <li>dev@${podling}.incubator.apache.org</li>
	      <li>commits@${podling}.incubator.apache.org</li>
	      <li>private@${podling}.incubator.apache.org</li>
	      </ul>
	      <p>
	        For initial community building it is usually appropriate to only have
	        a "dev" list, to keep the discussions focussed. Later add a "user" list
	        if needed.
	      </p>
	      <note>
	Commits under <code>http://svn.apache.org/repos/asf/incubator/<em>${podling}</em></code>
	will be emailed to <code>commits@${podling}.incubator.apache.org</code>.
	Any deviation will 
	require special configuration in the <code>asf-mailer.conf</code> file by the IPMC.
	      </note>
	      <p>
	      Mailing lists creation is a task for the <a href='#who-infra'>infrastructure team</a>. The
	      infrastructure team offers a tool that simplifies the creation of mailing lists.  You can access the
	      <a href="https://infra.apache.org/officers/mlreq/incubator" target="_new">Incubator Mailing List Request Form</a>
	      to request a list.  A notification will be sent to private@incubator when the lists have been created.
	      </p>
	      <p>
	      Remember to update the project status file with mailing list details. Prospective committers 
	      and mentors will need to subscribe. Email them once the status file has been updated. Inform
	      any existing mailing lists or forums previously used by the project.
	      </p>
	      <p>
	      Once the <code>commits</code> list is created, the project MUST review
	      the <code>/incubator/${podling}</code> tree, since any commits made prior
	      to the list's creation will have generated no email trail.
	      </p>
	      <section id='mail-archives'><title>Mail Archives</title>
	        <p>
	Archives at <a href='http://mail-archives.apache.org'>http://mail-archives.apache.org</a> for the public
	mailing lists will be setup as part of the mailing list creation process. No action is
	required by Mentors. The archives will be <a href='http://mail-archives.apache.org/mod_mbox/'>visible</a> 
	as soon as posts have been made (and moderated) to these lists.
	        </p>
	        <p>
		    You can also leverage <a href="https://lists.apache.org" target="_new">lists.apache.org</a> for 
		    mailing list archives.  There is a login link in the top right corner, which allows you to respond to
		    threads from within the web application.
		    </p>
	        <p>
	Many projects are independently archived externally (for example, at
	<a href='http://www.mail-archive.com/'>The Mail Archive</a> and 
	<a href='http://marc.info/?q=about'>MARC</a>)
	Independent archives help to
	increase project visibility as well as preserving a independent historic record.
	These subscriptions are not automatically created. If desired, subscribe manually.
	        </p><p>
	Subscriptions to news-to-mailing-list bridges (for example, <a href='http://www.nabble.com'>Nabble</a>)
	must also be created manually. Subscribing helps accessibility and visibility but Nabble news
	users may not be aware that they are posting to a mailing list.
	        </p>
	      </section>
	      <section id='mail-admin'><title>Mailing List Administration</title>
	        <p>
	Apache uses <a href='http://www.ezmlm.org/'>ezmlm</a>. See the 
	<a href='http://www.ezmlm.org/man/ezmlmman.html'>manual</a> and 
	committer <a href='http://www.apache.org/dev/committers.html#mail'>mail FAQ</a>
	for more details.
	        </p>
	      </section>
	      <section id='transition-mailing-lists'><title>Mailing List Transition</title>
	        <p>
	Independent mailing lists and groups are perfectly acceptable but development should
	happen on the official mailing lists at Apache. If a project has existing mailing lists,
	forums or groups the community needs to consider their future and plan for the transition
	to the official Apache mailing lists.
	        </p><p>
	It may be useful to move development first to the official lists followed gradually 
	by the user resources.
	        </p>
	        <p>
	        Note that subscribers of external mailing lists will not be automatically subscribed
	        to the new Incubator project mailing lists. Instead, a note should be posted to the
	        old external mailing list asking them to subscribe to the new list. If possible, add
	        a footer to the old mailing list with some instructions.
	        </p>
	      </section>
	      <section id='request-issue-tracking'><title>Issue Tracking</title>
	        <p>
		If any Mentor has project-creation karma (in the issue tracking system to be used) 
		then they should execute.
		If no Mentor has the required karma then file an INFRA issue using the 'new jira project' 
		type (not bug or request)
	        </p>
	        <p>
	Remember to post an email announcing that the issue tracker is available.
	        </p>
	      </section>
	      </section>


    <section id='glossary'><title>Glossary</title>
    <section id='who-committers'><title>Prospective Committers</title>
      <p>
      These are the people listed as initial committers in the proposal.
      </p>
    </section>
    
    <section id='who-infra'><title>Infrastructure Team</title>
      <p>
      Tasks that cannot safely be delegated to projects are handled by the Apache
      <a href='http://www.apache.org/dev/infra-volunteer.html'>Infrastructure team</a>. 
      The relevant instructions 
      <a href='http://www.apache.org/dev/infra-contact'>MUST be followed</a>. 
      JIRA is typically used to
      manage workflow. This allows progress to be easily tracked. 
      </p>    
      </section>
     <section id='who-auth-karma'><title>Incubator Access Authorization</title>
      <p>
      Special karma is required to authorize incubator access for committers. 
      This karma is limited to:
      </p>
      <ul>
        <li>PMC Chairs (past and present)</li>
        <li>Selected people in the Infrastructure team</li>
      </ul>
      <p>
      If any mentor has karma then they should authorize the committer.
      To grant authorization, update:
      </p>
         <source>
         infrastructure/trunk/subversion/authorization/asf-authorization-template
         </source>
       <p>
         Edit the file to add the new committer to the podling authorization:
       </p>
       <source>
  {podling}={mentor1},{mentor2},{new-committer}
       </source>
      <p>
      If no mentor has karma then an email should be posted to the IPMC private
      list requesting that the grant is performed. One of the IPMCers with karma
      will authorize the committer.
      </p>
     </section>
    </section>
    
  </body>
</document>
