<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Apache Ace Codebase Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section id="Apache+Ace+Codebase+Intellectual+Property+%28IP%29+Clearance+Status">
      <title>Apache Ace Codebase Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
    </section>
    <section id="Description">
      <title>Description</title>
      <p>Apache Ace is a software distribution framework that allows you to centrally 
      manage and distribute software components, configuration data and other artifacts 
      to target systems. It is built using OSGi and can be deployed in different topologies. 
      The target systems are usually also OSGi based, but don't have to be. This is the
      initial codebase and documentation which was originally developed at luminis.</p>
      <p>The source code and documentation are made available via Jira as issue
      <a href="https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/ACE-17">ACE-17</a>.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="Project+info">
      <title>Project info</title>
      <ul>
        <li>Because Apache Ace is still in the Incubator, the Incubator PMC is responsible for the code.</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>The code will be imported in the top level SVN directory for Ace.</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>Officer or member managing donation: Carsten Ziegeler (cziegeler)</li>
      </ul>
      <p>
        <em>Completed tasks are shown by the completion date (YYYY-MM-dd).</em>
      </p>
      <section id="Identify+the+codebase">
        <title>Identify the codebase</title>
        <table>
          <tr>
            <th>date</th>
            <th>item</th>
          </tr>
          <tr>
              <td>2009-06-17</td>
            <td>If applicable, make sure that any associated name does not
                already exist and is not already trademarked for an existing software
                product.</td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        <p>
MD5 or SHA1 sum for donated software: 26752157e61fa33c86487ff9c2c5f84f and e56fe5ee2c693439babf2d433ce955fe (ApacheA1.zip and ApacheA2.zip from ACE-17).
        </p>
        <section id="Copyright">
          <title>Copyright</title>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>date</th>
              <th>item</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2009-06-17</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that the papers that transfer rights to
                  the ASF been received. It is only necessary to transfer
                  rights for the package, the core code, and any new code
                  produced by the project.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>....-..-..</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that the files that have been donated
                  have been updated to reflect the new ASF copyright.</td>
            </tr>
          </table>
          <p>
Identify name recorded for software grant: Apache Ace
          </p>
        </section>
        <section id="Verify+distribution+rights">
          <title>Verify distribution rights</title>
            <p>
Corporations and individuals holding existing distribution rights:
            </p>
            <ul>
              <li>luminis</li>
            </ul>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>date</th>
              <th>item</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2009-06-17</td>
              <td>Check that all active committers have a signed CLA on
                  record.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>n/a</td>
              <td>Remind active committers that they are responsible for
                  ensuring that a Corporate CLA is recorded if such is
                  required to authorize their contributions under their
                  individual CLA.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>....-..-..</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that for all items included with the
                  distribution that is not under the Apache license, we have
                  the right to combine with Apache-licensed code and
                  redistribute.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>....-..-..</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that all items depended upon by the
                  project is covered by one or more of the following approved
                  licenses: Apache, BSD, Artistic, MIT/X, MIT/W3C, MPL 1.1, or
                  something with essentially the same terms.</td>
            </tr>
          </table>
          <p>Generally, the result of checking off these items will be a
             Software Grant, CLA, and Corporate CLA for ASF licensed code,
             which must have no dependencies upon items whose licenses that
             are incompatible with the Apache License.</p>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section id="Organizational+acceptance+of+responsibility+for+the+project">
        <title>Organizational acceptance of responsibility for the project
</title>
        <p>
Related VOTEs:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li><em>The VOTE thread accepting the donation may happen either
before or after IP clearance. Adoption by lazy concensus is acceptable but
not recommended.</em></li>
        </ul>
      </section>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
