<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>ActiveMQ Codebase Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
    </properties>
    <body>
        <section id="Codebase+IP+Clearance+TEMPLATE">
            <title>Codebase IP Clearance</title>
        </section>
        <section id="ActiveMQ+Codebase+Intellectual+Property+%28IP%29+Clearance+Status">
            <title>ActiveMQ Codebase Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
        </section>
        <section id="Description">
            <title>Description</title>
            <p>ActiveMQ is a fast open source JMS 1.1 provider and Message Fabric supporting clustering, peer networks,
                discovery, TCP, SSL, multicast, persistence, XA and integrates seamlessly into J2EE 1.4 containers,
                light weight containers and any Java application.</p>
        </section>
        <section id="Project+info">
            <title>Project info</title>
            <ul>
                <li>Which PMC will be responsible for the code: Apache Geronimo PMC</li>
            </ul>
            <ul>
                <li>Into which existing project/module: ActiveMQ will go into its own project</li>
            </ul>
            <ul>
                <li>Officer or member managing donation: James Strachan</li>
            </ul>
            <p>
                <em>Completed tasks are shown by the completion date (YYYY-MM-dd).</em>
            </p>
            <section id="Identify+the+codebase">
                <title>Identify the codebase</title>
                <table>
                    <tr>
                        <th>date</th>
                        <th>item</th>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>2006-02-18</td>
                        <td>Trademark, ActiveMQ, assigned to ASF</td>
                    </tr>
                </table>
                <section id="Copyright">
                    <title>Copyright</title>
                    <table>
                        <tr>
                            <th>date</th>
                            <th>item</th>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>2006-02-04</td>
                            <td>Check and make sure that the papers that transfer rights to
                                the ASF been received. It is only necessary to transfer
                                rights for the package, the core code, and any new code
                                produced by the project.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>2005-12-28</td>
                            <td>Check and make sure that the files that have been donated
                                have been updated to reflect the new ASF copyright.</td>
                        </tr>
                    </table>
                    <p>
                        Identify name recorded for software grant:
                        <em>the name of the grant as record
                            in the grants.txt document so that the grant can be easily identified</em>
                        <b>DONE</b>
                    </p>
                </section>
                <section id="Verify+distribution+rights">
                    <title>Verify distribution rights</title>
                    <p>
                        Corporations and individuals holding existing distribution rights:
                    </p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>
                            <em>For individuals, use the name as recorded on the committers page</em>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                    <table>
                        <tr>
                            <th>date</th>
                            <th>item</th>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                          <td>2006-01-20</td>
                          <td><p>Check that all active committers have a signed CLA on record.</p>
                            svn log https://svn.codehaus.org/activemq/branches/activemq-4-0 | grep "r[0-9][0-9]* | " |
                            sed "s/r[0-9][0-9]* | \(.*\) | .* | .*$/\1/" | sort | uniq
                            <p>All of the committers have a CLA on file at Apache. The following
                              table maps the unix user names to real names:</p>
                            <table>
                                <tr><td>aco</td><td>Adrian Co</td></tr>
                                <tr><td>ammulder</td><td>Aaron Mulder</td></tr>
                                <tr><td>brianm</td><td>Brian McCallister</td></tr>
                                <tr><td>chirino</td><td>Hiram Chirino</td></tr>
                                <tr><td>djcook</td><td>Dennis Cook</td></tr>
                                <tr><td>foconer</td><td>Frederick OConer</td></tr>
                                <tr><td>gnt</td><td>Guillaume Nodet</td></tr>
                                <tr><td>gregw</td><td>Gregory Wilkins</td></tr>
                                <tr><td>jgapuz</td><td>Joseph Gapuz</td></tr>
                                <tr><td>jlim</td><td>Jonas Lim</td></tr>
                                <tr><td>jstrachan</td><td>James Strachan</td></tr>
                                <tr><td>maguro</td><td>Alan Cabrera</td></tr>
                                <tr><td>pbrooke</td><td>TO BE DISCOVERED</td></tr>
                                <tr><td>pvillacorta</td><td>Patrick Villacorta</td></tr>
                                <tr><td>rajdavies</td><td>Robert Davies</td></tr>
                                <tr><td>rsaba</td><td>Ramzi Saba</td></tr>
                            </table>
                          </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>....-..-..</td>
                            <td>Remind active committers that they are responsible for
                                ensuring that a Corporate CLA is recorded if such is
                                required to authorize their contributions under their
                                individual CLA.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>....-..-..</td>
                            <td>Check and make sure that for all items included with the
                                distribution that is not under the Apache license, we have
                                the right to combine with Apache-licensed code and
                                redistribute.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>....-..-..</td>
                            <td>Check and make sure that all items depended upon by the
                                project is covered by one or more of the following approved
                                licenses: Apache, BSD, Artistic, MIT/X, MIT/W3C, MPL 1.1, or
                                something with essentially the same terms.</td>
                        </tr>
                    </table>
                    <p>Generally, the result of checking off these items will be a
                        Software Grant, CLA, and Corporate CLA for ASF licensed code,
                        which must have no dependencies upon items whose licenses that
                        are incompatible with the Apache License.</p>
                </section>
            </section>
            <section id="Organizational+acceptance+of+responsibility+for+the+project">
                <title>Organizational acceptance of responsibility for the project
                </title>
                <p>
                    Related VOTEs:
                </p>
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        <em>The VOTE thread accepting the donation may happen either
                            before or after IP clearance. Adoption by lazy concensus is acceptable but
                            not recommended.</em>
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </section>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>
