<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>apr-jlibtool
</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section id="jlibtool+Codebase+IP+Clearance+Status">
      <title>jlibtool Codebase IP Clearance Status
</title>
    </section>
    <section id="Description">
      <title>Description
</title>
      <p>A C-based replacement for libtool. One C file intended to be dropped
in to the repository. The last version I created is at:
</p>
      <p>http://www.apache.org/~jerenkrantz/jlibtool.c
</p>
    </section>
    <section id="Project+info">
      <title>Project info
</title>
      <ul>
        <li>Which PMC will be responsible for the code
</li>
      </ul>
      <p>APR
</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Into which existing project/module
</li>
      </ul>
      <p>apr CVS repository under the build/ directory.
</p>
      <p>
        <em>Completed tasks are shown by the completion date (YYYY-MM-dd).
</em>
      </p>
      <section id="Identify+the+codebase">
        <title>Identify the codebase
</title>
        <table>
          <tr>
            <th>date
</th>
            <th>item
</th>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>2004-07-08
</td>
            <td>If applicable, make sure that any associated name does not already
exist and check www.nameprotect.com to be sure that the name is not
already trademarked for an existing software product.
</td>
          </tr>
        </table>
      </section>
      <section id="Copyright">
        <title>Copyright
</title>
        <table>
          <tr>
            <th>date
</th>
            <th>item
</th>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>2004-07-08
</td>
            <td>Check and make sure that the papers that transfer rights to the ASF
been received. It is only necessary to transfer rights for the
package, the core code, and any new code produced by the project.
</td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        <p>(A software grant was faxed by Justin to Jim on 7/8/2004.)
</p>
        <table>
          <tr>
            <td>2004-07-08
</td>
            <td>Check and make sure that the files that have been donated have been
updated to reflect the new ASF copyright.
</td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        <p>(The copyright and license will be updated when it is committed.)
</p>
      </section>
      <section id="Verify+distribution+rights">
        <title>Verify distribution rights
</title>
        <table>
          <tr>
            <th>date
</th>
            <th>item
</th>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>2004-07-08
</td>
            <td>Check that all active committers have a signed CLA on record.
</td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        <p>(Yes.)
</p>
        <table>
          <tr>
            <td>2004-07-08
</td>
            <td>Remind active committers that they are responsible for ensuring that
a Corporate CLA is recorded if such is is required to authorize their
contributions under their individual CLA.
</td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        <p>(No corporate CLA needed.)
</p>
        <table>
          <tr>
            <td>2004-07-08
</td>
            <td>Check and make sure that for all items included with the distribution
that is not under the Apache license, we have the right to combine
with Apache-licensed code and redistribute.
</td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        <p>(The code was originally under the Apache 1.1 license - but will be
relicensed to ALv2.)
</p>
        <table>
          <tr>
            <td>2004-07-08
</td>
            <td>Check and make sure that all items depended upon by the project is
covered by one or more of the following approved licenses: Apache,
BSD, Artistic, MIT/X, MIT/W3C, MPL 1.1, or something with essentially
the same terms.
</td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        <p>(jlibtool has no external dependencies.)
</p>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section id="Organizational+acceptance+of+responsibility+for+the+project">
      <title>Organizational acceptance of responsibility for the project
</title>
      <ul>
        <li>Has the receiving PMC voted to accept it?
</li>
      </ul>
      <p>Yes, via dev@apr.
</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
