<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Commons RDF Codebase Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section id="Commons+RDF+Codebase+Intellectual+Property+IP+Clearance+Status">
      <title>Commons RDF Codebase Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
    </section>
    <section id="Description">
      <title>Description</title>
      <p>
        Commons RDF is a library which provides a set of interfaces for the RDF 
        1.1 concepts that can be used to expose common RDF 1.1 concepts using 
        common Java interfaces. The goal is to provide agreed and clear 
        interfaces that could be implemented by the upcoming versions of the 
        main Java toolkits (Apache Jena 3.0 and OpenRDF Sesame 4.0) as well as 
        reused by existing wrappers.
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="Project+info">
      <title>Project info</title>
      <ul>
        <li>Which PMC will be responsible for the code: Apache Commons</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>Into which existing project/module: Apache Commons Sanbox</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>Officer or member managing donation: @@TODO@@</li>
      </ul>
      <p>
        <em>Completed tasks are shown by the completion date (YYYY-MM-dd).</em>
      </p>
      <section id="Identify+the+codebase">
        <title>Identify the codebase</title>
        <table>
          <tr>
            <th>date</th>
            <th>item</th>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>2015-03-26</td>
            <td>
              No evidences of registration of the trademark for an existing 
              software product have been found.
          </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>2015-03-27</td>
            <td>
              Attached to <a href="https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/COMMONSRDF-1">COMMONSRDF-1</a> 
              as <strong>commons-rdf.bundle</strong> a bundle containing the master branch at github
              (<a href="https://github.com/commons-rdf/commons-rdf/tree/master">https://github.com/commons-rdf/commons-rdf/tree/master</a>
              by 2015-03-28 (tagged as 
              <a href="https://github.com/commons-rdf/commons-rdf/releases/tag/apache-import-20150327">apache-import-20150327</a>). 
              Software Grant Agreement signed and archived by ASF Secretary.
            </td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        <p>
          MD5 sum for donated software:  <tt>84095aae6d752b864e10181ec78ed299</tt>.
        </p>
        <section id="Copyright">
          <title>Copyright</title>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>date</th>
              <th>item</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2015-03-26</td>
              <td>
                Code was developed by Sergio Fernández (Apache ID wikier), Andy
                Seaborne (andy), Peter Ansell (ansell) and Stian Soiland-Reyes 
                (stain), who already are all ASF committers and have both ICLA 
                and CCLA with effect when the code was developed. 
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2015-03-29</td>
              <td>
                All code files now have standard ASF headers, license headers 
                added to other relevant files (POMs, XML etc).  RAT report is 
                clean.
              </td>
            </tr>
          </table>
          <p>
            Identify name recorded for software grant: n/a.
          </p>
        </section>
        <section id="Verify+distribution+rights">
          <title>Verify distribution rights</title>
          <p>
            Corporations and individuals holding existing distribution rights:
          </p>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>date</th>
              <th>item</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2015-03-26</td>
              <td>All committers have an ICLA on file</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2015-03-26</td>
              <td>All committers have an a CCLA on file that names him and has agreed to donate the code to the Apache Commons under the existing ICLA and CCLA</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2015-03-26</td>
              <td>There is no non-Apache licensed code present in the donated software</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2015-03-26</td>
              <td>All dependencies are other Apache projects or open source projects compatible with the Apache License</td>
            </tr>
          </table>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section id="Organizational+acceptance+of+responsibility+for+the+project">
        <title>Organizational acceptance of responsibility for the project</title>
        <p>
          Related VOTEs: n/a. 
        </p>
        <p>
          The original donation discussion can be found at the thread
          <a href="http://mail-archives.apache.org/mod_mbox/commons-dev/201407.mbox/%3C53CCEA51.9070801%40apache.org%3E">http://mail-archives.apache.org/mod_mbox/commons-dev/201407.mbox/%3C53CCEA51.9070801%40apache.org%3E</a>
        </p>
      </section>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
