<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>DeviceMap OpenDDR Codebase Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section id="DeviceMap+OpenDDR+Codebase+Intellectual+Property+%28IP%29+Clearance+Status">
      <title>OpenDDR Codebase Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
    </section>
    <section id="Description">
      <title>Description</title>
      <p>
        The OpenDDR codebase is attached to
        <a href="https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/DMAP-11">https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/DMAP-11</a> and consists of CSharp and Java API
        modules, and a Resources module which contains mobile device data. 
      </p>
      <p>
        Note that we won't accept the donation of the resources file at this stage, this IP clearance is 
        only about the two files mentioned below.
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="Project+info">
      <title>Project info</title>
      <ul>
        <li>The Incubator PMC is responsible for the code, as it its meant for an incubating project.</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>Code will be included in the DeviceMap podling codebase.</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>bdelacretaz is managing the donation process, as a DeviceMap incubation mentor.</li>
      </ul>
      <p>
        <em>Completed tasks are shown by the completion date (YYYY-MM-dd).</em>
      </p>
      <section id="Identify+the+codebase">
        <title>Identify the codebase</title>
        <table>
            <tr>
              <th>date</th>
              <th>item</th>
            </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>October 2nd, 2012</td>
            <td>2 files attached to DMAP-11:
                <br/>MD5 (OpenDDR-CSharp_1.0.0.10_src.zip) = 6f3281c7895986cc7bc80b6d8790d6d6
                <br/>MD5 (OpenDDR-Java_1.0.0.10_src.zip) = 1f7d0b5da0192fd514e4750abe712edf
            </td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        <section id="Copyright">
          <title>Copyright</title>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <td>September 12th, 2012</td>
              <td>The papers that transfer rights to
                  the ASF have been received: documents/grants/openddr.pdf in the foundation's private svn repository.
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Sept 24, 2012</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that the files that have been donated
                  have been updated to reflect the new ASF copyright: file headers
                  will be updated after importing the code in the DeviceMap svn repository.</td>
            </tr>
          </table>
        </section>
        <section id="Verify+distribution+rights">
          <title>Verify distribution rights</title>
            <p>
                Corporations and individuals holding existing distribution rights:
            </p>
            <ul>
                <li>OpenDDR LLC, represented by Werner Keil</li>
            </ul>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>date</th>
              <th>item</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Sept 24, 2012 (DMAP-11)</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that for all items included with the
                  distribution that is not under the Apache license, we have
                  the right to combine with Apache-licensed code and
                  redistribute.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>Sept 24, 2012 (DMAP-11)</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that all items depended upon by the
                  project is covered by one or more of the following approved
                  licenses: Apache, BSD, Artistic, MIT/X, MIT/W3C, MPL 1.1, or
                  something with essentially the same terms.</td>
            </tr>
          </table>
          <p>Generally, the result of checking off these items will be a
             Software Grant, CLA, and Corporate CLA for ASF licensed code,
             which must have no dependencies upon items whose licenses that
             are incompatible with the Apache License.</p>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section id="Organizational+acceptance+of+responsibility+for+the+project">
        <title>Organizational acceptance of responsibility for the project
</title>
        <p>
Related VOTEs:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li><em>VOTE thread accepting the donation: donation is mentioned in the
            DeviceMap incubation proposal at http://wiki.apache.org/incubator/DeviceMapProposal, no
            need for an additional vote.
           </em></li>
        </ul>
      </section>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
