<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Triplesec Codebase Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section id="Triplesec+Codebase+Intellectual+Property+%28IP%29+Clearance+Status">
      <title>Triplesec Codebase Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
    </section>
    <section id="Description">
      <title>Description</title>
      <p>
        Triplesec is a set of modules that enable the use of ApacheDS as an Identity 
        Management solution.  Triplesec includes the following items:  
      </p>
      <ul>
         <li>Custom authorization schema for LDAP</li>
         <li>Authorization API for accessing policy information within the directory</li>
         <li>A Swing based GUI for configuring and managing authz and authn policy</li>
         <li>ApacheDS integration with Jetty/Tomcat for administrative interfaces</li>
         <li>Kerberos SAM module for 2-factor Authentication</li>
         <li>Administration API</li>
         <li>Custom ApacheDS Interceptor for managing referencial integrity</li>
         <li>Installer Configurations</li>
         <li>Utilities for 2-factor Authentication Client</li>
         <li>Demo web applications for using Triplesec</li>
      </ul>
    </section>
    <section id="Project+info">
      <title>Project info</title>
      <ul>
        <li>The Directory PMC will be responsible for the code.</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>Since Triplesec is really the embelishment of ApacheDS for a specific function
               it will become a subproject of the Apache Directory TLP.
        </li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>Officer or member managing donation: Alex  Karasulu</li>
      </ul>
      <section id="Identify+the+codebase">
        <title>Identify the codebase</title>
        <table>
          <tr>
            <th>date</th>
            <th>item</th>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>2006-10-18</td>
            <td>If applicable, make sure that any associated name does not
                already exist and check www.nameprotect.com to be sure that
                the name is not already trademarked for an existing software
                product.</td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        <p>
SHA1 sum for donated software: 17b4b6e698a01a551d48d84b3d99cc63d357ee93 (1.0)
        </p>
        <section id="Copyright">
          <title>Copyright</title>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>date</th>
              <th>item</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2006-10-18</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that the papers that transfer rights to
                  the ASF been received. It is only necessary to transfer
                  rights for the package, the core code, and any new code
                  produced by the project.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2006-10-18</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that the files that have been donated
                  have been updated to reflect the new ASF copyright.</td>
            </tr>
          </table>
          <p>
Identify name recorded for software grant: Alex Karasulu
          </p>
        </section>
        <section id="Verify+distribution+rights">
          <title>Verify distribution rights</title>
            <p>
Corporations and individuals holding existing distribution rights:
            </p>
            <ul>
<li>
<em>For individuals, use the name as recorded on the committers page</em>
</li>
            </ul>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>date</th>
              <th>item</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2006-10-18</td>
              <td>Check that all active committers have a signed CLA on
                  record:  erodriguez, akarasulu, ersiner, elecharny, tbennett, trustin</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2006-10-18</td>
              <td>Remind active committers that they are responsible for
                  ensuring that a Corporate CLA is recorded if such is
                  required to authorize their contributions under their
                  individual CLA.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2006-10-18</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that for all items included with the
                  distribution that is not under the Apache license, we have
                  the right to combine with Apache-licensed code and
                  redistribute.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2006-10-18</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that all items depended upon by the
                  project is covered by one or more of the following approved
                  licenses: Apache, BSD, Artistic, MIT/X, MIT/W3C, MPL 1.1, or
                  something with essentially the same terms.</td>
            </tr>
          </table>
          <p>Generally, the result of checking off these items will be a
             Software Grant, CLA, and Corporate CLA for ASF licensed code,
             which must have no dependencies upon items whose licenses that
             are incompatible with the Apache License.</p>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section id="Organizational+acceptance+of+responsibility+for+the+project">
        <title>Organizational acceptance of responsibility for the project
</title>
        <p>
Related VOTEs: 
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>http://www.archivum.info/dev@directory.apache.org/2006-10/msg00017.html</li>
        </ul>
      </section>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
