<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>XYZ Codebase Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section id="Mitosis+Codebase+Intellectual+Property+%28IP%29+Clearance+Status">
      <title>Mitosis Codebase Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
    </section>
    <section id="Description">
      <title>Description</title>
      <p>Mitosis is a functional module for performing multimaster replication
with ApacheDS.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="Project+info">
      <title>Project info</title>
      <ul>
        <li>The Directory PMC will be responsible for the code</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>The Mitosis code will <b>NOT</b> constitute a new project under the
Directory TLP but will be incorporated into the existing ApacheDS code base.</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>Officer or member managing donation: Alex Karasulu</li>
      </ul>
      <section id="Identify+the+codebase">
        <title>Identify the codebase</title>
        <table>
          <tr>
            <th>date</th>
            <th>item</th>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>2006-10-17</td>
            <td>Mitosis: the name is NOT significant since Mitosis will not 
become a separate product but will be integrated directly into ApacheDS</td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        <p>
SHA1 sum for donated software: 4aafaae35ea0ce9dc4e21fac4ce437005db17ee3 (1.0).
        </p>
        <section id="Copyright">
          <title>Copyright</title>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>date</th>
              <th>item</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2006-10-17</td>
              <td>Software grant filed with Secretary and Directory VP</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2006-10-17</td>
              <td>New ASF copyright has been assigned in file headers.</td>
            </tr>
          </table>
          <p>
Identify name recorded for software grant: Alex Karasulu
          </p>
        </section>
        <section id="Verify+distribution+rights">
          <title>Verify distribution rights</title>
            <ul>
<li>
<em>For individuals, use the name as recorded on the committers page</em>
</li>
            </ul>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>date</th>
              <th>item</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2006-10-17</td>
              <td>Check that all active committers have a signed CLA on
                  record.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2006-10-17</td>
              <td>Remind active committers that they are responsible for
                  ensuring that a Corporate CLA is recorded if such is
                  required to authorize their contributions under their
                  individual CLA.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2006-10-17</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that for all items included with the
                  distribution that is not under the Apache license, we have
                  the right to combine with Apache-licensed code and
                  redistribute.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2006-10-17</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that all items depended upon by the
                  project is covered by one or more of the following approved
                  licenses: Apache, BSD, Artistic, MIT/X, MIT/W3C, MPL 1.1, or
                  something with essentially the same terms.</td>
            </tr>
          </table>
          <p>Generally, the result of checking off these items will be a
             Software Grant, CLA, and Corporate CLA for ASF licensed code,
             which must have no dependencies upon items whose licenses that
             are incompatible with the Apache License.</p>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section id="Organizational+acceptance+of+responsibility+for+the+project">
        <title>Organizational acceptance of responsibility for the project
</title>
        <p>
Related VOTEs: 
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>http://www.mail-archive.com/dev@directory.apache.org/msg08136.html</li>
        </ul>
      </section>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
