<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>HornetQ Codebase Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section id="HornetQ+Codebase+Intellectual+Property+%28IP%29+Clearance+Status">
      <title>HornetQ Codebase Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
    </section>
    <section id="Description">
      <title>Description</title>
      <p>HornetQ is an open source project to build a multi-protocol, embeddable, very high performance, clustered, asynchronous messaging system.  
        This is large code grant of the whole project.  HornetQ was previously licensed under the Apache License 2.0 and is now being granted to the ASF.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="Project+info">
      <title>Project info</title>
      <ul>
        <li>Which PMC will be responsible for the code: Apache ActiveMQ PMC</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>Into which existing project/module: New ActiveMQ subproject</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>Officer or member managing donation: Hiram Chirino</li>
      </ul>
      <p>
        <em>Completed tasks are shown by the completion date (YYYY-MM-dd).</em>
      </p>
      <section id="Identify+the+codebase">
        <title>Identify the codebase</title>
        <table>
          <tr>
            <th>date</th>
            <th>item</th>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>2014-07-10</td>
            <td>https://github.com/hornetq/hornetq/archive/90d43fbc158a0e6e3028c7179dbcf984757b88fb.zip
              (MD5: c41d7dafd24c02dd040217f46255c64e )
              </td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        <section id="Copyright">
          <title>Copyright</title>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>date</th>
              <th>item</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2015-04-13</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that the papers that transfer rights to
                  the ASF been received. It is only necessary to transfer
                  rights for the package, the core code, and any new code
                  produced by the project.
                  <br/>
                  A CCLA was recorded cover grant from 'Red Hat, Inc. as - David Ingham:dingham@redhat.com:Signed Corp CLA for Clebert Suconic, Andy Taylor, Justin Bertram, Youg Hao Gao, Martyn Taylor for hornetq, hornetq.utils.UUID, hornetq.utils.base64, hornetq.utils.json'
               </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2015-05-27</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that the files that have been donated
                  have been updated to reflect the new ASF copyright.</td>
            </tr>
          </table>
          <p>
              Identify name recorded for software grant: CCLA was recorded as <em>Red Hat, Inc. - David Ingham:dingham@redhat.com:Signed Corp CLA for Clebert Suconic, Andy Taylor, Justin Bertram, Youg Hao Gao, Martyn Taylor for hornetq, hornetq.utils.UUID, hornetq.utils.base64, hornetq.utils.json</em>
          </p>
        </section>
        <section id="Verify+distribution+rights">
          <title>Verify distribution rights</title>
            <p>
Corporations and individuals holding existing distribution rights:
            </p>
            <ul>
              <li>Red Hat, Inc.</li>
            </ul>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>date</th>
              <th>item</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2015-04-13</td>
              <td>Check that all active committers have a signed CLA on
                  record.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2015-04-13</td>
              <td>Remind active committers that they are responsible for
                  ensuring that a Corporate CLA is recorded if such is
                  required to authorize their contributions under their
                  individual CLA.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2015-05-27</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that for all items included with the
                  distribution that is not under the Apache license, we have
                  the right to combine with Apache-licensed code and
                  redistribute.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2015-05-27</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that all items depended upon by the
                  project is covered by one or more of the following approved
                  licenses: Apache, BSD, Artistic, MIT/X, MIT/W3C, MPL 1.1, or
                  something with essentially the same terms.</td>
            </tr>
          </table>
          <p>Generally, the result of checking off these items will be a
             Software Grant, CLA, and Corporate CLA for ASF licensed code,
             which must have no dependencies upon items whose licenses that
             are incompatible with the Apache License.</p>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section id="Organizational+acceptance+of+responsibility+for+the+project">
        <title>Organizational acceptance of responsibility for the project
</title>
        <p>
Related VOTEs:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="http://activemq.markmail.org/thread/asmdcnxetocg4jnb">http://activemq.markmail.org/thread/asmdcnxetocg4jnb</a></li>
        </ul>
      </section>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
