<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>HTrace Codebase Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section id="Description">
      <title>Description</title>
      <p>HTrace is a tracing framework for use with distributed systems written in java.
      HTrace is currently in a repository on the Cloudera public github at htrace.org.
      This clearance is for HTrace at https://github.com/cloudera/htrace as of commit
      22c4fac69eef035d8cc2819febdc4ac14c1fb99a .
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="Project+info">
      <title>Project info</title>
      <ul>
        <li>Which PMC will be responsible for the code: HTrace (incubating) PMC</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>Into which existing project/module: HTrace (incubating)</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>Officer or member managing donation: Michael Stack (stack)</li>
      </ul>
      <p>
        <em>Completed tasks are shown by the completion date (YYYY-MM-dd).</em>
      </p>
      <section id="Identify+the+codebase">
        <title>Identify the codebase</title>
        <table>
          <tr>
            <th>date</th>
            <th>item</th>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>2014-11-11</td>
            <td>https://github.com/cloudera/htrace as of commit 22c4fac69eef035d8cc2819febdc4ac14c1fb99a or
              see tarball at https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/attachment/12680909/htrace.22c4fac69eef035d8cc2819febdc4ac14c1fb99a.tgz
              Its md5 is ed8901e64ff35e93fb78ebd1c9056385
            </td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        <section id="Copyright">
          <title>Copyright</title>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>date</th>
              <th>item</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2014-11-11</td>
              <td>Software Grant of HTrace project mailed to secretary@apache.
                Had to be resent 2014-11-26 signed by a VP of Cloudera, Inc.
                (Peter Cooper Ellis).</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2014-11-27</td>
              <td>Grant ack'd by secretary@apache
                <pre>To: Peter Cooper Ellis &lt;stack@apache.org>
                    Cc: secretary@apache.org
                    Message-ID: &lt;5477bcd888b9c_1d8dc1e0f8608b9@whimsy-vm.mail>
                    Subject: Your Grant sent to Apache Secretary
                    Mime-Version: 1.0
                    Content-Type: text/plain;
                     charset=UTF-8
                     Content-Transfer-Encoding: 7bit

                     Dear Peter Cooper Ellis,

                     This message acknowledges receipt of the following document, which has been filed in the Apache Software Foundation records:

                       Grant from Cloudera, Inc.

                       -- Craig L Russell
                       Secretary, Apache Software Foundation</pre>

                </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>N/A</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that the files that have been donated
                have been updated to reflect the new ASF copyright.
                <i>The project was already licensed Apache 2.0</i>.</td>
            </tr>
          </table>
          <p>
Identify name recorded for software grant: <em>Cloudera, Inc., file cloudera-htrace.pdf, for htrace</em>
          </p>
        </section>
        <section id="Verify+distribution+rights">
          <title>Verify distribution rights</title>
            <p>
Corporations and individuals holding existing distribution rights:
            </p>
            <ul>
<li>
  Cloudera, Inc.
</li>
            </ul>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>date</th>
              <th>item</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2014-11-11</td>
              <td>All active committers have a signed CLA on record.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2014-11-11</td>
              <td>Remind active committers that they are responsible for
                  ensuring that a Corporate CLA is recorded if such is
                  required to authorize their contributions under their
                  individual CLA.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2014-11-11</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that for all items included with the
                  distribution that is not under the Apache license, we have
                  the right to combine with Apache-licensed code and
                  redistribute.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2014-11-11</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that all items depended upon by the
                  project is covered by one or more of the following approved
                  licenses: Apache, BSD, Artistic, MIT/X, MIT/W3C, MPL 1.1, or
                  something with essentially the same terms.</td>
            </tr>
          </table>
          <p>Generally, the result of checking off these items will be a
             Software Grant, CLA, and Corporate CLA for ASF licensed code,
             which must have no dependencies upon items whose licenses that
             are incompatible with the Apache License.</p>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section id="Organizational+acceptance+of+responsibility+for+the+project">
        <title>Organizational acceptance of responsibility for the project
</title>
        <p>
Related VOTEs:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>The VOTE thread accepting the donation is up on the dev
            mailing list for htrace: http://mail-archives.apache.org/mod_mbox/incubator-htrace-dev/201411.mbox/browser 
</li>
        </ul>
      </section>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
