<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Jakarta Commons CSV Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section id="Jakarta+Commons+CSV+Codebase+Intellectual+Property+%28IP%29+Clearance+Status">
      <title>Jakarta Commons CSV Codebase Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
    </section>
    <section id="Description">
      <title>Description</title>
      <p><em>Implementation of a CSV (Comma Separated Values) parser in Java. </em></p>
    </section>
    <section id="Project+info">
      <title>Project info</title>
      <ul>
        <li>Which PMC will be responsible for the code: <strong>Jakarta</strong></li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>Into which existing project/module: <strong>Jakarta Commons</strong></li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>Officer or member managing donation: Henri Yandell (bayard@apache.org)</li>
      </ul>
      <p>
        <em>Completed tasks are shown by the completion date (YYYY-MM-dd).</em>
      </p>
      <section id="Identify+the+codebase">
        <title>Identify the codebase</title>
        <table>
          <tr>
            <th>date</th>
            <th>item</th>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>not applicable</td>
            <td>If applicable, make sure that any associated name does not
                already exist and check www.nameprotect.com to be sure that
                the name is not already trademarked for an existing software
                product.</td>
          </tr>
        </table>
          <p>
MD5 sum for donated software: <strong>aaa5ffe2c1413ed1ece266663a4764f8</strong> (OpenSSL 0.9.7d).
          </p>
        <section id="Copyright">
          <title>Copyright</title>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>date</th>
              <th>item</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2005-12-12</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that the papers that transfer rights to
                  the ASF been received. It is only necessary to transfer
                  rights for the package, the core code, and any new code
                  produced by the project.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2005-12-16</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that the files that have been donated
                  have been updated to reflect the new ASF copyright.</td>
            </tr>
          </table>
          <p>
Identify name recorded for software grant:
          </p>
<quote><pre>
Netcetera AG / Joachim Hagger, CTO
   "CSV parsing and printing software including test and build
    files (all delivered as source code). The file contributed is
    found at:
      ftp:ftp.netcetera.ch/pub/csvparser.jar
    Dated 2005-06-05, 10:42:00, size 42KB"      
</pre></quote>
        </section>
        <section id="Verify+distribution+rights">
          <title>Verify distribution rights</title>
          <p>
Corporations and individuals holding existing distribution rights:
          </p>
          <ul>
            <li>
Netcetera AG. (Our contact: Stefan Rufer (<em>stefan.rufer@netcetera.ch</em>))
            </li>
          </ul>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>date</th>
              <th>item</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>not applicable</td>
              <td>Check that all active committers have a signed CLA on
                  record.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>not applicable</td>
              <td>Remind active committers that they are responsible for
                  ensuring that a Corporate CLA is recorded if such is
                  required to authorize their contributions under their
                  individual CLA.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>not applicable</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that for all items included with the
                  distribution that is not under the Apache license, we have
                  the right to combine with Apache-licensed code and
                  redistribute.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>not applicable</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that all items depended upon by the
                  project is covered by one or more of the following approved
                  licenses: Apache, BSD, Artistic, MIT/X, MIT/W3C, MPL 1.1, or
                  something with essentially the same terms.</td>
            </tr>
          </table>
          <p>Generally, the result of checking off these items will be a
             Software Grant, CLA, and Corporate CLA for ASF licensed code,
             which must have no dependencies upon items whose licenses that
             are incompatible with the Apache License.</p>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section id="Organizational+acceptance+of+responsibility+for+the+project">
        <title>Organizational acceptance of responsibility for the project</title>
        <ul>
          <li>Has the receiving PMC voted to accept it? 
<a href='http://mail-archives.apache.org/mod_mbox/jakarta-commons-dev/200508.mbox/%3c31cc37360508312212278c97c5@mail.gmail.com%3e'>Yes</a></li>
          <li>Subversion URL for official record of initial codebase: <a href='http://svn.apache.org/repos/asf/jakarta/grants/'>(not currently available)</a>.</li>
        </ul>
      </section>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
