<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>maven-patch-plugin Codebase Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section id="maven-patch-plugin+Codebase+Intellectual+Property+%28IP%29+Clearance+Status">
      <title>maven-patch-plugin Codebase Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
    </section>
    <section id="Description">
      <title>Description</title>
      <p>This is a plugin for Maven 2.x that applies patch files to an existing project's source. It currently does
      this by delegation to an external patch executable.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="Project+info">
      <title>Project info</title>
      <ul>
        <li>Which PMC will be responsible for the code: Apache Maven</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>Into which existing project/module: Maven (Plugins)</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>Officer or member managing donation: Brett Porter</li>
      </ul>
      <p>
        <em>Completed tasks are shown by the completion date (YYYY-MM-dd).</em>
      </p>
      <section id="Identify+the+codebase">
        <title>Identify the codebase</title>
        <table>
          <tr>
            <th>date</th>
            <th>item</th>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>2007-06-08</td>
            <td>If applicable, make sure that any associated name does not
                already exist and is not already trademarked for an existing software
                product.</td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        <p>
MD5 or SHA1 sum for donated software:  (<em>Note versioned software used to calculate sum in parentheses</em>).
        </p>
        <p>
        72a2359b104c37e364ac5c0b573c1999  maven-patch-plugin.zip (md5sum; OS X 10.4.10, build 8R2232)
        </p>
        <section id="Copyright">
          <title>Copyright</title>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>date</th>
              <th>item</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2007-07-05</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that the files that have been donated
                  have been updated to reflect the new ASF license.</td>
            </tr>
          </table>
          <p>
            Contributed by original authors under the terms of their existing ASF CLA.
          </p>
        </section>
        <section id="Verify+distribution+rights">
          <title>Verify distribution rights</title>
            <p>
Corporations and individuals holding existing distribution rights:
            </p>
            <ul>
<li>John Dennis Casey</li>
<li>Codehaus</li>
            </ul>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>date</th>
              <th>item</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2007-06-08</td>
              <td>Check that all active committers have a signed CLA on
                  record.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2007-06-08</td>
              <td>Remind active committers that they are responsible for
                  ensuring that a Corporate CLA is recorded if such is
                  required to authorize their contributions under their
                  individual CLA.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2007-06-08</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that for all items included with the
                  distribution that is not under the Apache license, we have
                  the right to combine with Apache-licensed code and
                  redistribute.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2007-06-08</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that all items depended upon by the
                  project is covered by one or more of the following approved
                  licenses: Apache, BSD, Artistic, MIT/X, MIT/W3C, MPL 1.1, or
                  something with essentially the same terms.</td>
            </tr>
          </table>
          <p>Generally, the result of checking off these items will be a
             Software Grant, CLA, and Corporate CLA for ASF licensed code,
             which must have no dependencies upon items whose licenses that
             are incompatible with the Apache License.</p>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section id="Organizational+acceptance+of+responsibility+for+the+project">
        <title>Organizational acceptance of responsibility for the project
</title>
        <p>
Related VOTEs: 
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>Contributed to sandbox by lazy consensus - vote will be undertaken for
            promotion and release.</li>
        </ul>
      </section>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
