<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>KeepAliveFilters.zip Codebase Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section id="KeepAliveFilters+zip+Codebase+Intellectual+Property+%28IP%29+Clearance+Status">
      <title>KeepAliveFilters.zip Codebase Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
    </section>
    <section id="Description">
      <title>Description</title>
      <p>KeepAliveFilters.zip contains just 5 extension classes for Apache MINA that sends keep-alive messages.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="Project+info">
      <title>Project info</title>
      <ul>
        <li>The MINA PMC will be responsible for this code.</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>The code will be imported into MINA</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>Trustin Lee is managing the donation.</li>
      </ul>
      <p>
        <em>Completed tasks are shown by the completion date (YYYY-MM-dd).</em>
      </p>
      <section id="Identify+the+codebase">
        <title>Identify the codebase</title>
        <table>
          <tr>
            <td>2007-10-17</td>
            <td>http://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/attachment/12352063/KeepAliveFilters.zip</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>Package name: org.apache.mina.filter.keepalive</td>
            <td>If applicable, make sure that any associated name does not
                already exist and is not already trademarked for an existing software
                product.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>SHA1 sum of http://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/attachment/12352063/KeepAliveFilters.zip</td>
            <td>SHA1 (KeepAliveFilters.zip) = 14fdd3d3a177e04a086214113faf234d90105107</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>MD5 sum of http://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/attachment/12352063/KeepAliveFilters.zip</td>
            <td>MD5 (KeepAliveFilters.zip) = e6853127e69341fd7e19c4a936174506</td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        <p>
            We will be importing the subversion repository.
        </p>
        <section id="Copyright">
          <title>Copyright</title>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>date</th>
              <th>item</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2007-10-17</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that the papers that transfer rights to
                  the ASF been received. It is only necessary to transfer
                  rights for the package, the core code, and any new code
                  produced by the project.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2007-10-17</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that the files that have been donated
                  have been updated to reflect the new ASF copyright. - <strong>There's no copyright header in the source code.  However, the contributor already agreed to license for includion in ASF works by attaching the file to the ASF JIRA.</strong></td>
            </tr>
          </table>
          <p>
Identify name recorded for software grant: <em>KeepAliveFilters.zip</em> 
          </p>
        </section>
        <section id="Verify+distribution+rights">
          <title>Verify distribution rights</title>
            <p>
Corporations and individuals holding existing distribution rights:
            </p>
            <ul>
              <li><strong>KeepAliveFilters.zip has been attached to <a href="http://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/DIRMINA-354">a JIRA issue</a> checked with 'Licensed for inclusion in ASF works.  Therefore, it effectively means that the author of the code agreed with donation.</strong>  Consequently, <em>everyone</em> not in violation of the Apache Software License 2.0 has distribution rights.</li>
              <li>Contributions have been made by Eero Nevalainen</li>
            </ul>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>date</th>
              <th>item</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2007-10-17</td>
              <td>Check that all active committers have a signed CLA on
                  record.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2007-10-17</td>
              <td>Remind active committers that they are responsible for
                  ensuring that a Corporate CLA is recorded if such is
                  required to authorize their contributions under their
                  individual CLA.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2007-10-17</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that for all items included with the
                  distribution that is not under the Apache license, we have
                  the right to combine with Apache-licensed code and
                  redistribute.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2007-10-17</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that all items depended upon by the
                  project is covered by one or more of the following approved
                  licenses: Apache, BSD, Artistic, MIT/X, MIT/W3C, MPL 1.1, or
                  something with essentially the same terms.</td>
            </tr>
          </table>
          <p>Generally, the result of checking off these items will be a
             Software Grant, CLA, and Corporate CLA for ASF licensed code,
             which must have no dependencies upon items whose licenses that
             are incompatible with the Apache License.</p>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section id="Organizational+acceptance+of+responsibility+for+the+project">
        <title>Organizational acceptance of responsibility for the project
</title>
        <p>
Related VOTEs: 
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li><em><a href="http://www.nabble.com/-VOTE--Import-KeepAlive-functionality-contribution-under-MINA-PMC-tf4525278s16868.html">vote on mina-dev</a></em></li>
        </ul>
      </section>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
