<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Redback Codebase Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section id="redback+Codebase+Intellectual+Property+%28IP%29+Clearance+Status">
      <title>Redback Codebase Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
    </section>
    <section id="Description">
      <title>Description</title>
      <p>Redback is a security framework which provide mechanism for authentication, authorization and user management. It's used by Apache Archiva and Apache Continuum.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="Project+info">
      <title>Project info</title>
      <ul>
        <li>The Archiva PMC is responsible for the code.</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>The code will be imported into http://svn.apache.org/repos/asf/archiva/redback as part a of the Archiva project.</li>
        <li>http://svn.codehaus.org/redback/redback/ -> http://svn.apache.org/repos/asf/archiva/redback/redback-core</li>
        <li>http://svn.codehaus.org/redback/components/ -> http://svn.apache.org/repos/asf/archiva/redback/redback-components</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>Olivier Lamy is the Apache member responsible for managing the donation process.</li>
      </ul>
      <p>
        <em>Completed tasks are shown by the completion date (YYYY-MM-dd).</em>
      </p>
      <section id="Identify+the+codebase">
        <title>Identify the codebase</title>
        <table>
          <tr>
            <th>date</th>
            <th>item</th>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>2012-04-03</td>
            <td>If applicable, make sure that any associated name does not
                already exist and is not already trademarked for an existing software
                product.</td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        <p>
        The code is available here : 
          <ul>
            <li>core http://s.apache.org/redback-core-import (md5: 1a33794d321429f3c13c1f8e94127e3d )</li>
            <li>components http://s.apache.org/redback-components-import (md5: 355f82d535f7f159fe8f8d74c4e6b492 )</li>
          </ul>
        </p>
        <section id="Copyright">
          <title>Copyright</title>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>date</th>
              <th>item</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>N/A</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that the papers that transfer rights to
                  the ASF been received. It is only necessary to transfer
                  rights for the package, the core code, and any new code
                  produced by the project.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2012-04-06</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that the files that have been donated
                  have been updated to reflect the new ASF copyright.</td>
            </tr>
          </table>
          <p>No grant needed as the product was developed by ASF committers under ASF license at Codehaus.</p>
        </section>
        <section id="Verify+distribution+rights">
          <title>Verify distribution rights</title>
            <p>
Corporations and individuals holding existing distribution rights:
            </p>
            <ul>
<li>Codehaus.org</li>
            </ul>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>date</th>
              <th>item</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2012-04-03</td>
              <td>Check that all active committers have a signed CLA on
                  record.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2012-04-03</td>
              <td>Remind active committers that they are responsible for
                  ensuring that a Corporate CLA is recorded if such is
                  required to authorize their contributions under their
                  individual CLA.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2012-04-03</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that for all items included with the
                  distribution that is not under the Apache license, we have
                  the right to combine with Apache-licensed code and
                  redistribute.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2012-04-03</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that all items depended upon by the
                  project is covered by one or more of the following approved
                  licenses: Apache, BSD, Artistic, MIT/X, MIT/W3C, MPL 1.1, or
                  something with essentially the same terms.</td>
            </tr>
          </table>
          <p>All developers have CLAs on record with Apache</p>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section id="Organizational+acceptance+of+responsibility+for+the+project">
        <title>Organizational acceptance of responsibility for the project</title>
        <p>
          Ip cleadance mail thread http://s.apache.org/l3G
        </p>
        <p>
          2012-04-06: Sources imported.
        </p>
      </section>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
