<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Shale Clay Plugin for Eclipse Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section id="Shale+Clay+Plugin+for+Eclipse+Intellectual+Property+%28IP%29+Clearance+Status">
      <title>Shale Clay Plugin for Eclipse Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
    </section>
    <section id="Description">
      <title>Description</title>

      <p>The Shale Clay Plugin for the Eclipse IDE is a visual editor targeted at creating 
             and maintaining Shale Clay component meta-data.  The Shale Clay XML component 
             meta-data is used to create JavaSever Faces (JSF) managed views.  The plugin supports 
             auto-detection of Clay component definitions in an Eclipse workspace.  It allows 
             XML component definitions to be extended through drag-and-drop from a component 
             palette.  It also provides auto-completion of managed bean names and methods.  
             The tool supports both visual and text modes.
      </p>  
      <p>The plugin is a significant contribution donated by Ryan Wynn and can be found attached to the 
            <a href="https://issues.apache.org/struts/browse/SHALE-444">SHALE-444 JIRA ticket</a>.   The 
            codebase consists of a single Eclipse plugin project that has dependencies with 
            several Apache Commons libraries besides the shale-core and shale-clay libraries.
            </p>

    </section>
    <section id="Project+info">
      <title>Project info</title>
      <ul>
        <li>The Shale PMC will be responsible for the code contribution.</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>We foresee this codebase becoming a separate project within the tools offerings 
            under the Shale community.</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>Officer or member managing donation:</li>
        <ul><li>Wendy Smoak (ASF Member)</li>
            <li>Gary VanMatre (Shale PMC)</li>
        </ul>
      </ul>
      <p>
        <em>Completed tasks are shown by the completion date (YYYY-MM-dd).</em>
      </p>
      <section id="Identify+the+codebase">
        <title>Identify the codebase</title>
        <table>
          <tr>
            <th>date</th>
            <th>item</th>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>2007-07-11</td>
            <td>If applicable, make sure that any associated name does not
                already exist and is not already trademarked for an existing software
                product.  (No existing product.  Complies with Eclipse Foundation
                naming guidelines.)</td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        <p>
MD5 sum for donated software:  b038c63fced4b25024c5d41f995296e9 .
        </p>
        <section id="Copyright">
          <title>Copyright</title>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>date</th>
              <th>item</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2007-07-11</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that the papers that transfer rights to
                  the ASF been received. It is only necessary to transfer
                  rights for the package, the core code, and any new code
                  produced by the project.  (ICLA on file from Ryan Wynn.)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2007-07-11</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that the files that have been donated
                  have been updated to reflect the new ASF copyright.</td>
            </tr>
          </table>
          <p>
Identify name recorded for software grant: <em>N/A - single contributor with
ICLA on file.</em> 
          </p>
        </section>
        <section id="Verify+distribution+rights">
          <title>Verify distribution rights</title>
            <p>
Corporations and individuals holding existing distribution rights:
            </p>
            <ul>
<li>
<em>Ryan Wynn</em>
</li>
            </ul>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>date</th>
              <th>item</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2007-07-11</td>
              <td>Check that all active committers have a signed CLA on
                  record.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2007-07-11</td>
              <td>Remind active committers that they are responsible for
                  ensuring that a Corporate CLA is recorded if such is
                  required to authorize their contributions under their
                  individual CLA.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>N/A</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that for all items included with the
                  distribution that is not under the Apache license, we have
                  the right to combine with Apache-licensed code and
                  redistribute.  (N/A - all included items are under the
                  Apache license.)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2007-07-11</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that all items depended upon by the
                  project is covered by one or more of the following approved
                  licenses: Apache, BSD, Artistic, MIT/X, MIT/W3C, MPL 1.1, or
                  something with essentially the same terms.</td>
            </tr>
          </table>
          <p>Generally, the result of checking off these items will be a
             Software Grant, CLA, and Corporate CLA for ASF licensed code,
             which must have no dependencies upon items whose licenses that
             are incompatible with the Apache License.</p>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section id="Organizational+acceptance+of+responsibility+for+the+project">
        <title>Organizational acceptance of responsibility for the project
</title>
        <p>
Related VOTEs: 
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="http://www.nabble.com/-VOTE--Accept-the-Shale-Clay-Plugin-for-Eclipse-contribution-t4065440.html">
          [VOTE] Accept the Shale Clay Plugin for Eclipse contribution</a></li>
        </ul>
      </section>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>

