<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>Sling HApi Tools - Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
    </properties>
    <body>
        <section id="Sling+HApi+IP+Clearance+Status">
            <title>Sling HApi Tools - Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
        </section>
        <section id="Description">
            <title>Description</title>
            <p>The Sling HApi Tools provide a set of Hypermedia API tools for Sling</p>
        </section>
        <section id="Project+info">
            <title>Project info</title>
            <ul>
                <li>Apache Sling PMC will be responsible for the code</li>
            </ul>
            <ul>
                <li>This contribution will be placed under contrib</li>
            </ul>
            <ul>
                <li>Officer or member managing donation: Bertrand Delacretaz (bdelacretaz@apache.org)</li>
            </ul>
            <p>
                <em>Completed tasks are shown by the completion date (YYYY-MM-dd).</em>
            </p>
            <section id="Identify+the+codebase">
                <title>Identify the codebase</title>
                <table>
                    <tr>
                        <th>date</th>
                        <th>item</th>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>2014-11-03</td>
                        <td>source code is attached to the SLING-4513 ticket as hapi.tar.gz</td>
                    </tr>
                </table>
                <p>
                    SHA1 sum for donated software:
                    <br/>  
                    SHA1(hapi.tar.gz)= 321dd447d956d1766d9d3d36a056e02b7220afc2
                </p>
                <section id="Copyright">
                    <title>Copyright</title>
                    <table>
                        <tr>
                            <th>date</th>
                            <th>item</th>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>2015-08-17</td>
                            <td>Check and make sure that the papers that transfer rights to
                                the ASF been received. It is only necessary to transfer
                                rights for the package, the core code, and any new code
                                produced by the project.
                                <br/>
                                Software grant registered as <em>private/documents/grants/adobe-hapi.pdf</em> on August 13, 2015.
                                </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>2015-08-17</td>
                            <td>Check and make sure that the files that have been donated
                                have been updated to reflect the new ASF copyright: done, one 
                                of the donated files still had the Adobe copyright, this was not
                                on purpose as confirmed by Andrei Dulvac in SLING-4778 - he has
                                authorized the ASF to make the change after importing the code.
                                </td>
                        </tr>
                    </table>
                    <p>
                        Identify name recorded for software grant: <em>Adobe Systems Inc.</em>
                    </p>
                </section>
                <section id="Verify+distribution+rights">
                    <title>Verify distribution rights</title>
                    <p>
                        Corporations and individuals holding existing distribution rights:
                    </p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>
                            <em>Adobe Systems Inc.</em>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                    <table>
                        <tr>
                            <th>date</th>
                            <th>item</th>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>2015-08-17</td>
                            <td>Check that all active committers have a signed CLA on
                                record.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>2015-08-17</td>
                            <td>Remind active committers that they are responsible for
                                ensuring that a Corporate CLA is recorded if such is
                                required to authorize their contributions under their
                                individual CLA.</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>2015-08-17</td>
                            <td>Check and make sure that for all items included with the
                                distribution that is not under the Apache license, we have
                                the right to combine with Apache-licensed code and
                                redistribute.
                                </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>2015-08-17</td>
                            <td>Check and make sure that all items depended upon by the
                                project is covered by one or more of the following approved
                                licenses: Apache, BSD, Artistic, MIT/X, MIT/W3C, MPL 1.1, or
                                something with essentially the same terms.
                                </td>
                        </tr>
                    </table>
                    <p>Generally, the result of checking off these items will be a
                        Software Grant, CLA, and Corporate CLA for ASF licensed code,
                        which must have no dependencies upon items whose licenses that
                        are incompatible with the Apache License.</p>
                </section>
            </section>
            <section id="Organizational+acceptance+of+responsibility+for+the+project">
                <title>Organizational acceptance of responsibility for the project
                </title>
                <p>
                    Related VOTEs:
                </p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Vote on dev@sling: Message-ID: &lt;CACfebH9p6J3CAyHOWUrgmcicBKV3Orb_kBOPNZDK3Gb9ePR9wA@mail.gmail.com&gt; on dev@sling.a.o
                    </li>
                    <li>Vote result on dev@sling: Message-ID: &lt;CACfebH8153g6ZCyYhefuEyc+R78TwGfZYeaEGyvZiOZKpMu-SQ@mail.gmail.com&gt;
                    </li>
                    <li>Lazy consensus vote on general@incubator: 
                        Message-ID: &lt;CAEWfVJkM46fjSeNt+1mZ=RyzTgRXA4rDBQhsgt6JNz=FDfEZ6w@mail.gmail.com&gt;
                    </li>
                    <li>Lazy consensus vote result on general@incubator: 
                        Message-ID: &lt;CAEWfVJmUnqKYdF1TZmDtUCR3_VWSTyYvtOhnLaPCA6Uuw=4J6w@mail.gmail.com&gt;
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </section>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>
