<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Quest Data Connector Codebase Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section id="Quest+Data+Connector+Codebase+Intellectual+Property+%28IP%29+Clearance+Status">
      <title>Quest Data Connector Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
    </section>
    <section id="Description">
      <title>Description</title>
      <p>The current built-in Oracle connector in Sqoop suffers from various performance problems as it does not use any knowledge of how Oracle stores and represents data on the underlying filesystem. Quest Data Connector, created by Quest Software (later acquired by Dell), is an improved Sqoop connector that optimizes the data transfer with a reduced overhead on the Oracle database.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="Project+info">
      <title>Project info</title>
      <ul>
        <li>Sqoop PMC will be responsible for the code.</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>Into which existing project/module: The connector will be merge into Sqoop "trunk" branch.</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>Officer or member managing donation: Arvind Prabhakar</li>
      </ul>
      <p>
        <em>Completed tasks are shown by the completion date (2014-06-29).</em>
      </p>
      <section id="Identify+the+codebase">
        <title>Identify the codebase</title>
        <table>
          <tr>
            <th>date</th>
            <th>item</th>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>2014-01-22</td>
            <td>Quest Data Connector was independently developed and maintained by Quest Software
                who owned all the associated trademarks and rights. The software itself has been
                released multiple times and open sourced under Apache License Version 2.0
                at https://github.com/QuestSoftwareTCD/OracleSQOOPconnector</td>
          </tr>
        </table>

        <!--
        <p>
MD5 or SHA1 sum for donated software:  (<em>Note versioned software used to calculate sum in parentheses</em>).
        </p>
        -->

        <section id="Copyright">
          <title>Copyright</title>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>date</th>
              <th>item</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2014-02-03</td>
              <td>Software grant received by ASF Secretary.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2014-02-04</td>
              <td>Verified ownership of existing code commit by commit.</td>
            </tr>
          </table>
        </section>
        <section id="Verify+distribution+rights">
          <title>Verify distribution rights</title>
            <p> Corporations and individuals holding existing distribution rights: </p>
            <ul>
              <li>
                <em>For individuals, use the name as recorded on the committers page</em>
              </li>
            </ul>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>date</th>
              <th>item</th>
            </tr>
            <!-- <tr>
              <td>....-..-..</td>
              <td>Check that all active committers have a signed CLA on
                  record.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>....-..-..</td>
              <td>Remind active committers that they are responsible for
                  ensuring that a Corporate CLA is recorded if such is
                  required to authorize their contributions under their
                  individual CLA.</td>
            </tr> -->
            <tr>
              <td>2012-02-04</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that for all items included with the
                  distribution that is not under the Apache license, we have
                  the right to combine with Apache-licensed code and
                  redistribute.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2012-02-04</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that all items depended upon by the
                  project is covered by one or more of the following approved
                  licenses: Apache, BSD, Artistic, MIT/X, MIT/W3C, MPL 1.1, or
                  something with essentially the same terms.</td>
            </tr>
          </table>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section id="Organizational+acceptance+of+responsibility+for+the+project">
        <title>Organizational acceptance of responsibility for the project
</title>
        <p>
Related VOTE RESULT Message ID: 86D9B2BCB5DB0A44B392EB9AD6CF2AA312430C98@ALVMBXW02.prod.quest.corp on dev@sqoop.apache.org mailing list, on 01/28/2014.
        </p>
      </section>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
