<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>XWork Codebase Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
    </properties>
    <body>
        <section id="XWork+Codebase+Intellectual+Property+%28IP%29+Clearance+Status">
            <title>XWork Codebase Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
        </section>
        <section id="Description">
            <title>Description</title>
            <p>
                XWork is a command-pattern framework that is used as the foundation of Struts 2
            </p>
            <p>
                The code will become a submodule of Apache Struts 2
            </p>
            <p>
                The current codebase can be found at the Subversion repository:
                <strong>https://svn.opensymphony.com/svn/xwork/</strong>.
                The donated codebase has the original repository revision 2082.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="Project+info">
            <title>Project info</title>
            <ul>
                <li>Which PMC will be responsible for the code: Apache Struts PMC</li>
            </ul>
            <ul>
                <li>Into which existing project/module: Apache Struts 2</li>
            </ul>
            <ul>
                <li>Officer or member managing donation: Martin Cooper</li>
            </ul>
            <p>
                <em>Completed tasks are shown by the completion date (YYYY-MM-dd).</em>
            </p>
            <section id="Identify+the+codebase">
                <title>Identify the codebase</title>
                <table>
                    <tr>
                        <th>date</th>
                        <th>item</th>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>2009-11-30</td>
                        <td>If applicable, make sure that any associated name does not
                            already exist and is not already trademarked for an existing software
                            product.
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                </table>
                <p>
                    MD5 or SHA1 sum for donated software: MD5 861277c220c6b579802e8a4fc963596e (available at <a href="https://issues.apache.org/struts/browse/WW-3248">WW-3248</a>)
                </p>
                <section id="Copyright">
                    <title>Copyright</title>
                    <table>
                        <tr>
                            <th>date</th>
                            <th>item</th>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>2009-12-10</td>
                            <td>Check and make sure that the papers that transfer rights to
                                the ASF been received. It is only necessary to transfer
                                rights for the package, the core code, and any new code
                                produced by the project.
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>2009-12-27</td>
                            <td>Check and make sure that the files that have been donated
                                have been updated to reflect the new ASF copyright.
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                    </table>
                    <p>
                        Identify name recorded for software grant: OpenSymphony XWork
                    </p>
                </section>
                <section id="Verify+distribution+rights">
                    <title>Verify distribution rights</title>
                    <p>
                        Corporations and individuals holding existing distribution rights:
                    </p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>
                            OpenSymphony
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                    <table>
                        <tr>
                            <th>date</th>
                            <th>item</th>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>2009-10-07</td>
                            <td>
                                <p>Check that all active committers have a signed CLA on record.</p>
                                <p>All of the committers have a CLA on file with The Apache Software Foundation. The following table maps the unix user names to real names:</p>
                                <table>
                                    <tr><td>davenewton</td><td>Dave Newton</td></tr>
                                    <tr><td>davsclaus</td><td>Claus Ibsen</td></tr>
                                    <tr><td>jcarreira</td><td>Jason Carreira</td></tr>
                                    <tr><td>jmitchell</td><td>James Mitchell</td></tr>
                                    <tr><td>lukasz03</td><td>Lukasz Lenart</td></tr>
                                    <tr><td>mrdon</td><td>Don Brown</td></tr>
                                    <tr><td>musachy</td><td>Musachy Barroso</td></tr>
                                    <tr><td>phil</td><td>Philip Luppens</td></tr>
                                    <tr><td>plightbo</td><td>Patrick Lightbody</td></tr>
                                    <tr><td>rainerh</td><td>Rainer Hermanns</td></tr>
                                    <tr><td>rgielen</td><td>Rene Gielen</td></tr>
                                    <tr><td>roughley</td><td>Ian Roughley</td></tr>
                                    <tr><td>tm_jee</td><td>Toby Jee</td></tr>
                                    <tr><td>tschneider22</td><td>Tom Schneider</td></tr>
                                    <tr><td>wesw</td><td>Wes Wannemacher</td></tr>
                                </table>
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>2009-10-07</td>
                            <td>Remind active committers that they are responsible for
                                ensuring that a Corporate CLA is recorded if such is
                                required to authorize their contributions under their
                                individual CLA.
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>2009-12-03</td>
                            <td>Check and make sure that for all items included with the
                                distribution that is not under the Apache license, we have
                                the right to combine with Apache-licensed code and
                                redistribute.
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td>2009-12-03</td>
                            <td>Check and make sure that all items depended upon by the
                                project is covered by one or more of the following approved
                                licenses: Apache, BSD, Artistic, MIT/X, MIT/W3C, MPL 1.1, or
                                something with essentially the same terms.
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                    </table>
                    <p>Generally, the result of checking off these items will be a
                        Software Grant, CLA, and Corporate CLA for ASF licensed code,
                        which must have no dependencies upon items whose licenses that
                        are incompatible with the Apache License.
                    </p>
                </section>
            </section>
            <section id="Organizational+acceptance+of+responsibility+for+the+project">
                <title>Organizational acceptance of responsibility for the project
                </title>
                <p>
                    Related VOTEs:
                </p>
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        The VOTE thread accepting the donation can be found in the mailng list <a href="http://www.mail-archive.com/dev@struts.apache.org/msg35426.html">archives</a>.
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </section>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>
