<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Apache UIMA TextMarker Codebase Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section id="Apache+UIMA+TextMarker+Codebase+Intellectual+Property+%28IP%29+Clearance+Status">
      <title>Apache UIMA TextMarker Codebase Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
    </section>
    <section id="Description">
      <title>Description</title>
  <p>Apache UIMA TextMarker is a rule-based script language supported by Eclipse-based
tooling. The language is designed to enable rapid development of text processing applications
within UIMA. A special focus lies on the intuitive and flexible domain specific language for
defining patterns of annotations. The Eclipse-based tooling for TextMarker, called the TextMarker
Workbench, was created to support the user and to facilitate every step when writing TextMarker
rules. Both the TextMarker rule language and the TextMarker Workbench integrate smoothly with
Apache UIMA.
  </p>
  <p>
      TextMarker is contributed as zip-file with multiple java projects and a zip file with wiki content.
  </p>
    </section>
    <section id="Project+info">
      <title>Project info</title>
      <ul>
        <li>The UIMA PMC is responsible for the code.</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>The code will be imported into https://svn.apache.org/repos/asf/uima/sandbox/TextMarker as part a of the UIMA project.</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>Marshall Schor, Jörn Kottmann and Peter Klügl are responsible for managing the donation process.</li>
      </ul>
      <p>
        <em>Completed tasks are shown by the completion date (YYYY-MM-dd).</em>
      </p>
      <section id="Identify+the+codebase">
        <title>Identify the codebase</title>
        <table>
          <tr>
            <th>date</th>
            <th>item</th>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>2013-01-08</td>
            <td>If applicable, make sure that any associated name does not
                already exist and is not already trademarked for an existing software
                product.</td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        <p>
        The code is available here: https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/attachment/12487004/TextMarker.zip.
        </p>
        <section id="Copyright">
          <title>Copyright</title>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>date</th>
              <th>item</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2013-01-08</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that the papers that transfer rights to
                  the ASF been received. It is only necessary to transfer
                  rights for the package, the core code, and any new code
                  produced by the project.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2013-01-08</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that the files that have been donated
                  have been updated to reflect the new ASF copyright.</td>
            </tr>
          </table>
          <p>
Identify name recorded for software grant: <em>TextMarker</em>,
and a Software Grant recorded with  Corporate CLAs:
          </p>
          <ul>
            <li>Signed Corp CLA for Peter Klügl for TextMarker by the University of Würzburg, Germany</li>
          </ul>
        </section>
        <section id="Verify+distribution+rights">
          <title>Verify distribution rights</title>
            <p>
Corporations and individuals holding existing distribution rights:
            </p>
            <ul>
<li><em>Universität Würzburg, Germany</em></li>
<li><em>Peter Klügl</em></li>
            </ul>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>date</th>
              <th>item</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2013-01-08</td>
              <td>Check that all active committers have a signed CLA on
                  record.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2013-01-08</td>
              <td>Remind active committers that they are responsible for
                  ensuring that a Corporate CLA is recorded if such is
                  required to authorize their contributions under their
                  individual CLA.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2013-01-08</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that for all items included with the
                  distribution that is not under the Apache license, we have
                  the right to combine with Apache-licensed code and
                  redistribute.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2013-01-08</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that all items depended upon by the
                  project is covered by one or more of the following approved
                  licenses: Apache, BSD, Artistic, MIT/X, MIT/W3C, MPL 1.1, or
                  something with essentially the same terms.</td>
            </tr>
          </table>
          <p>Generally, the result of checking off these items will be a
             Software Grant, CLA, and Corporate CLA for ASF licensed code,
             which must have no dependencies upon items whose licenses that
             are incompatible with the Apache License.</p>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section id="Organizational+acceptance+of+responsibility+for+the+project">
        <title>Organizational acceptance of responsibility for the project
</title>
        <p>
Related VOTEs:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>http://markmail.org/message/igdc65lyqpvmmz3h</li>
          <li>http://mail-archives.apache.org/mod_mbox/uima-dev/201108.mbox/ajax/%3C4E3691EA.6040401%40uni-wuerzburg.de%3E</li>
    </ul>
      </section>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
