<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>uimaFIT Codebase Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section id="uimaFIT+Codebase+Intellectual+Property+%28IP%29+Clearance+Status">
      <title>uimaFIT Codebase Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
    </section>
    <section id="Description">
      <title>Description</title>
      <p>uimaFIT provides Java annotations for describing UIMA components
        which can be used to directly describe the UIMA components in Java code
        without the need for traditional UIMA XML descriptors. This greatly
        simplifies refactoring a component definition (e.g., changing a
        configuration parameter name). uimaFIT also makes it easy to instantiate
        UIMA components without using XML descriptor files by providing
        convenient factory methods. This makes uimaFIT an ideal library for
        testing UIMA components because the component can be easily instantiated
        and invoked without requiring a descriptor file to be created first.
        uimaFIT is very useful in research environments in which
        programmatic/dynamic instantiation of UIMA pipelines can simplify
        experimentation. For example, when performing 10-fold cross-validation
        across a number of experimental conditions, it can be quite laborious
        to create a different set of descriptor files for each run, or even a
        script which generates such descriptor files. uimaFIT is type system
        agnostic and does not depend on (or provide) a specific type system
      </p>
      <p>
        uimaFIT is contributed as a multi-module Maven project.
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="Project+info">
      <title>Project info</title>
      <ul>
        <li>The UIMA PMC is responsible for the code.</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>The code will be imported into https://svn.apache.org/repos/asf/uima/sandbox/uimafit as part a of the UIMA project.</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>Marshal Schor and Richard Eckart de Castilho are responsible for managing the donation process.</li>
      </ul>
      <p>
        <em>Completed tasks are shown by the completion date (YYYY-MM-dd).</em>
      </p>
      <section id="Identify+the+codebase">
        <title>Identify the codebase</title>
        <table>
          <tr>
            <th>date</th>
            <th>item</th>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>2012-12-10</td>
            <td>If applicable, make sure that any associated name does not
              already exist and is not already trademarked for an existing software
              product.</td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        <p>
          The code is available here: http://code.google.com/p/uimafit/downloads/detail?name=uimaFIT-grant-staging-rev-919.zip and
          SHA1 sum for donated software: 010d2f2880cd502b08a6e2659041aa025689cd20
          (<em>Note versioned software used to calculate sum in parentheses</em>).
        </p>
        <section id="Copyright">
          <title>Copyright</title>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>date</th>
              <th>item</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2012-12-11</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that the papers that transfer rights to
                the ASF been received. It is only necessary to transfer
                rights for the package, the core code, and any new code
                produced by the project.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2012-12-27</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that the files that have been donated
                have been updated to reflect the new ASF copyright.</td>
            </tr>
          </table>
          <p>
            Identify name recorded for software grant: <em>uimaFIT source code and wiki contents</em>, 
            and a Software Grant recorded with  Corporate CLAs: 
          </p>
          <ul>
            <li>Signed Corp CLA for Philip Ogren, Steven Bethard, Chris Roeder, Philipp Wetzler for
              uimaFIT by the Regents of the University of Colorado, CO, USA</li>
            <li>Signed Corp CLA for Niklas Jakob, Richard Eckart de Castilho, Shuo Yang, Torsten
              Zesch for uimaFIT by the Technische Universität Darmstadt, Germany</li>
          </ul>
        </section>
        <section id="Verify+distribution+rights">
          <title>Verify distribution rights</title>
          <p>
            Corporations and individuals holding existing distribution rights:
          </p>
          <ul>
            <li><em>Regents of the University of Colorado, CO, USA</em></li>
            <li><em>Technische Universität Darmstadt, Germany</em></li>
            <li><em>Steven Bethard</em></li>
            <li><em>Fabio Mancinelli</em></li>
          </ul>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>date</th>
              <th>item</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2012-12-25</td>
              <td>Check that all active committers have a signed CLA on
                record.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2012-12-25</td>
              <td>Remind active committers that they are responsible for
                ensuring that a Corporate CLA is recorded if such is
                required to authorize their contributions under their
                individual CLA.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2012-12-25</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that for all items included with the
                distribution that is not under the Apache license, we have
                the right to combine with Apache-licensed code and
                redistribute.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2012-12-25</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that all items depended upon by the
                project is covered by one or more of the following approved
                licenses: Apache, BSD, Artistic, MIT/X, MIT/W3C, MPL 1.1, or
                something with essentially the same terms.</td>
            </tr>
          </table>
          <p>Generally, the result of checking off these items will be a
            Software Grant, CLA, and Corporate CLA for ASF licensed code,
            which must have no dependencies upon items whose licenses that
            are incompatible with the Apache License.</p>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section id="Organizational+acceptance+of+responsibility+for+the+project">
        <title>Organizational acceptance of responsibility for the project
        </title>
        <p>
          Related VOTEs:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>http://markmail.org/message/rkru7hrwblhc6tvk</li>
          <li>http://mail-archives.apache.org/mod_mbox/uima-dev/201210.mbox/ajax/%3CFF46A436B80DCD43A9D7E64209F33ACB460A30C2%40FANSWORTH.ukp.informatik.tu-darmstadt.de%3E</li>
        </ul>
      </section>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
