<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Usergrid Codebase Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section id="Usergrid+Codebase+Intellectual+Property+%28IP%29+Clearance+Status">
      <title>Usergrid Codebase Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
    </section>
    <section id="Description">
      <title>Description</title>
      <p>The initial donation of code from Apigee to Apache to create the Usergrid Podling, portal, stack, SDKs and UGC CLI tool included.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="Project+info">
      <title>Project info</title>
      <ul>
        <li>Which PMC will be responsible for the code: The Usergrid PPMC</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>Into which existing project/module: Usergrid</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>Officer or member managing donation: johndament</li>
      </ul>
      <p>
        <em>Completed tasks are shown by the completion date (YYYY-MM-dd).</em>
      </p>
      <section id="Identify+the+codebase">
        <title>Identify the codebase</title>
        <table>
          <tr>
            <th>date</th>
            <th>item</th>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>2015-02-09</td>
            <td>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/PODLINGNAMESEARCH-67 resolved indicating the name is OK to use.</td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        <p>
MD5 or SHA1 sum for donated software:  (<em>Note versioned software used to calculate sum in parentheses</em>).
        </p>
        <section id="Copyright">
          <title>Copyright</title>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>date</th>
              <th>item</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2015-04-15</td>
              <td>SGA sent and processed by the secretary on 2015-04-15</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2015-04-15</td>
              <td>All source files now have an Apache header.</td>
            </tr>
          </table>
          <p>
Identify name recorded for software grant: <em>the name of the grant as record
in the grants.txt document so that the grant can be easily identified</em>
          </p>
        </section>
        <section id="Verify+distribution+rights">
          <title>Verify distribution rights</title>
            <p>
Corporations and individuals holding existing distribution rights:
            </p>
            <ul>
<li>
<em>For individuals, use the name as recorded on the committers page</em>
</li>
            </ul>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>date</th>
              <th>item</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2015-04-15</td>
              <td>All initial committers have an ICLA on file. CCLA received as well for Apigee team members.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2015-04-15</td>
              <td>Members from Apigee have CCLA on file from initial entry.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2015-04-15</td>
              <td>Non-Apache compliant source removed from code base.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2015-04-15</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that all items depended upon by the
                  project is covered by one or more of the following approved
                  licenses: Apache, BSD, Artistic, MIT/X, MIT/W3C, MPL 1.1, or
                  something with essentially the same terms.
                  Software includes some Cat-B licensed binaries, only
                  within the binary distribution.</td>
            </tr>
          </table>
          <p>Generally, the result of checking off these items will be a
             Software Grant, CLA, and Corporate CLA for ASF licensed code,
             which must have no dependencies upon items whose licenses that
             are incompatible with the Apache License.</p>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section id="Organizational+acceptance+of+responsibility+for+the+project">
        <title>Organizational acceptance of responsibility for the project
</title>
        <p>
Related VOTEs:
        </p>
        <ul>
	      <li><a href="http://mail-archives.apache.org/mod_mbox/incubator-general/201504.mbox/%3CCAOqetn8LDncVrmwX6PUO61fcgS1UnMTwbFoyX2fdu1QCuTAOjw%40mail.gmail.com%3E">Vote to accept code donation</a></li>
        </ul>
      </section>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
