<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Apache Wicket Codebase Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section id="Wicket+Codebase+Intellectual+Property+%28IP%29+Clearance+Status">
      <title>Wicket Free Guide Intellectual Property (IP) Clearance Status</title>
    </section>
    <section id="Description">
      <title>Description</title>
      <p>Andrea del Bene has written a book documenting Apache Wicket, and it is intended to become the official reference guide for Wicket.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="Project+info">
      <title>Project info</title>
      <ul>
        <li>The Wicket PMC is responsible for the document.</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>It will be incorporated into our public website as the official online documentation.</li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>Officer or member managing donation: Martijn Dashorst</li>
      </ul>
      <p>
        <em>Completed tasks are shown by the completion date (YYYY-MM-dd).</em>
      </p>
      <section id="Identify+the+codebase">
        <title>Identify the codebase</title>
        <table>
          <tr>
            <th>date</th>
            <th>item</th>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>2013-08-18</td>
            <td>The document that's donated is <a href="http://code.google.com/p/wicket-guide/">hosted at google code</a>. I have attached a version of the document to https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/WICKET-5321 (MD5: f4e4ac60fd17be8cdff2a78c75109506)</td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        <section id="Copyright">
          <title>Copyright</title>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>date</th>
              <th>item</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2013-07-28</td>
              <td>Done. Check and make sure that the papers that transfer rights to
                  the ASF been received. It is only necessary to transfer
                  rights for the package, the core code, and any new code
                  produced by the project.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2013-08-20</td>
              <td>Done. Check and make sure that the files that have been donated
                  have been updated to reflect the new ASF copyright.</td>
            </tr>
          </table>
          <p>
Identify name recorded for software grant: andrea-del-bene-wicket.pdf
          </p>
        </section>
        <section id="Verify+distribution+rights">
          <title>Verify distribution rights</title>
            <p>
Corporations and individuals holding existing distribution rights:
            </p>
            <ul>
<li>
Andrea del Bene (adelbene)
</li>
            </ul>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>date</th>
              <th>item</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2013-08-18</td>
              <td>n/a. Check that all active committers have a signed
				  CLA on record.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2013-08-18</td>
              <td>n/a. Remind active committers that they are responsible for
                  ensuring that a Corporate CLA is recorded if such is
                  required to authorize their contributions under their
                  individual CLA.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2013-08-18</td>
              <td>Done: Andrea recorded a SGA with secretary@ on 2013-07-28.
				  Check and make sure that for all items included with the
                  distribution that is not under the Apache license, we have
                  the right to combine with Apache-licensed code and
                  redistribute.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>2013-08-18</td>
              <td>n/a. Check and make sure that all items depended upon by the
                  project is covered by one or more of the following approved
                  licenses: Apache, BSD, Artistic, MIT/X, MIT/W3C, MPL 1.1, or
                  something with essentially the same terms.</td>
            </tr>
          </table>
          <p>Generally, the result of checking off these items will be a
             Software Grant, CLA, and Corporate CLA for ASF licensed code,
             which must have no dependencies upon items whose licenses that
             are incompatible with the Apache License.</p>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section id="Organizational+acceptance+of+responsibility+for+the+project">
        <title>Organizational acceptance of responsibility for the project
</title>
        <p>
Related VOTEs:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="http://mail-archives.apache.org/mod_mbox/wicket-dev/201308.mbox/%3cCAB63Y-ckdAYVODc9A6cnh9cAeuea4oiL-wgn3ZPO6kx7GjR5rw@mail.gmail.com%3e">Wicket dev@ list</a></li>
        </ul>
      </section>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
