<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>ibatis
</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section id="iBATIS+Project+Incubation+Status">
      <title>iBATIS Project Incubation Status
</title>
      <p>This page tracks the project status, incubator-wise. For more general
project status, look on the project website.
</p>
<p><span class="graduated">The iBATIS project graduated on 2005-04-27</span></p>
    </section>
    <section id="Description">
      <title>Description
</title>
      <p>The iBATIS Data Mapper framework makes it easier to use a database
with Java and .NET applications. iBATIS couples objects with stored
procedures or SQL statements using a XML descriptor.
</p>
      <p>Simplicity is the biggest advantage of the iBATIS Data Mapper over
object relational mapping tools. To use iBATIS Data Mapper you rely
on your own objects, XML, and SQL. There is little to learn that you
don't already know.
</p>
      <p>With iBATIS Data Mapper you have the full power of both SQL and
stored procedures at your fingertips
</p>
    </section>
    <section id="News">
      <title>News
</title>
      <ul>
        <li>Proposal accepted by Incubator PMC on 16 August 2004
</li>
      </ul>
    </section>
    <section id="Incubation+status+reports">
      <title>Incubation status reports
</title>
      <ul>
        <li>(2004-10-17) All needed CLAs are on file. Code grants are in transit.
Accounts for the committers are created. Mailing lists are created.
Committers are subscribing. The Jira setup for the project is being
finalized. The project incubator page is created. Committers are
preparing the SourceForge CVS and third-party SVN for import to
Apache.
</li>
      </ul>
    </section>
    <section id="Project+info">
      <title>Project info
</title>
      <table>
        <tr>
          <th>item
</th>
          <th>type
</th>
          <th>reference
</th>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Website
</td>
          <td>www
</td>
          <td>.
</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>.
</td>
          <td>wiki
</td>
          <td>.
</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Mailing list
</td>
          <td>dev
</td>
          <td>ibatis-dev incubator.apache.org
</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>.
</td>
          <td>user
</td>
          <td>ibatis-user-java incubator.apache.org
</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>.
</td>
          <td>user
</td>
          <td>ibatis-user-cs incubator.apache.org
</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Issue tracking
</td>
          <td>Jira
</td>
          <td>.
</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Source code
</td>
          <td>Subversion
</td>
          <td>incubator/ibatis
</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Mentors
</td>
          <td>husted
</td>
          <td>Ted Husted
</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Committers
</td>
          <td>cbegin
</td>
          <td>Clinton Begin
</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>.
</td>
          <td>gbayon
</td>
          <td>Gilles Bayon
</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>.
</td>
          <td>bgoodin
</td>
          <td>Brandon Goodin
</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>.
</td>
          <td>lmeadors
</td>
          <td>Larry Meadors
</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>.
</td>
          <td>roberto
</td>
          <td>Roberto Rabe
</td>
        </tr>
      </table>
      <ul>
        <li>Websites for prior SourceForge projects:

          <a href="http://ibatis.com/">(Java)
</a>
          <a href="http://ibatisnet.sf.net/">(.NET)
</a>
        </li>
      </ul>
    </section>
    <section id="Incubation+work+items">
      <title>Incubation work items
</title>
      <section id="Project+Setup">
        <title>Project Setup
</title>
        <p>This is the first phase on incubation, needed to start the project at
Apache.
</p>
        <p>
          <em>Item assignment is shown by the Apache id.
</em>
          <em>Completed tasks are shown by the completion date (YYYY-MM-dd).
</em>
        </p>
        <section id="Identify+the+project+to+be+incubated">
          <title>Identify the project to be incubated
</title>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>status
</th>
              <th>item
</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>DONE
</td>
              <td>Make sure that the requested project name does not already exist and
check www.nameprotect.com to be sure that the name is not already
trademarked for an existing software product.
</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>DONE
</td>
              <td>If request from an existing Apache project to adopt an external
package, then ask the Apache project for the cvs module and mail
address names.
</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>DONE
</td>
              <td>If request from outside Apache to enter an existing Apache project,
then post a message to that project for them to decide on acceptance.
</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>DONE
</td>
              <td>If request from anywhere to become a stand-alone PMC, then assess the
fit with the ASF, and create the lists and modules under the
incubator address/module names if accepted.
</td>
            </tr>
          </table>
        </section>
        <section id="Interim+responsibility">
          <title>Interim responsibility
</title>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>status
</th>
              <th>item
</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>DONE
</td>
              <td>Identify all the Mentors for the incubation, by asking all that can
be Mentors.
</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>DONE
</td>
              <td>Subscribe all Mentors on the pmc and general lists.
</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>DONE
</td>
              <td>Give all Mentors access to all incubator CVS modules. (to be done by
PMC chair)
</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>DONE
</td>
              <td>Tell Mentors to track progress in the file
'incubator/projects/{project.name}.cwiki'
</td>
            </tr>
          </table>
        </section>
        <section id="Copyright">
          <title>Copyright
</title>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>status
</th>
              <th>item
</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>DONE
</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that the papers that transfer rights to the ASF
been received. It is only necessary to transfer rights for the
package, the core code, and any new code produced by the project.
</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>DONE
</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that the files that have been donated have been
updated to reflect the new ASF copyright.
</td>
            </tr>
          </table>
        </section>
        <section id="Verify+distribution+rights">
          <title>Verify distribution rights
</title>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>status
</th>
              <th>item
</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>DONE
</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that for all code included with the distribution
that is not under the Apache license, e have the right to combine
with Apache-licensed code and redistribute.
</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>DONE
</td>
              <td>Check and make sure that all source code distributed by the project
is covered by one or more of the following approved licenses: Apache,
BSD, Artistic, MIT/X, MIT/W3C, MPL 1.1, or something with essentially
the same terms.
</td>
            </tr>
          </table>
        </section>
        <section id="Establish+a+list+of+active+committers+%21">
          <title>Establish a list of active committers !
</title>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>status
</th>
              <th>item
</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>DONE
</td>
              <td>Check that all active committers have submitted a contributors
agreement.
</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>DONE
</td>
              <td>Add all active committers in the STATUS file.
</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>DONE
</td>
              <td>Ask root for the creation of committers' accounts on cvs.apache.org.
</td>
            </tr>
          </table>
        </section>
        <section id="Infrastructure+%21">
          <title>Infrastructure !
</title>
          <table>
            <tr>
              <th>status
</th>
              <th>item
</th>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>DONE
</td>
              <td>Ask infrastructure to create source repository modules and grant the
committers karma.
</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>DONE
</td>
              <td>Ask infrastructure to set up and archive Mailing lists.
</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>DONE
</td>
              <td>Decide about and then ask infrastructure to setup an issuetracking
system (Bugzilla, Scarab, Jira).
</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>DONE
</td>
              <td>Migrate the project to our infrastructure.
</td>
            </tr>
          </table>
        </section>
        <section id="Project+specific">
          <title>Project specific
</title>
          <p>
            <em>Add project specific tasks here.
</em>
          </p>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section id="Incubation">
        <title>Incubation
</title>
        <p>These action items have to be checked for during the whole incubation
process.
</p>
        <p>
          <em>These items are not to be signed as done during incubation, as they
may change during incubation.
</em>
          <em>They are to be looked into and described in the status reports and
completed in the request for incubation signoff.
</em>
        </p>
        <section id="Collaborative+Development">
          <title>Collaborative Development
</title>
          <ul>
            <li>DONE - Have all of the active long-term volunteers been identified
and acknowledged as committers on the project?
</li>
            <li>DONE - Are there three or more independent committers? (The legal
definition of independent is long and boring, but basically it means
that there is no binding relationship between the individuals, such
as a shared employer, that is capable of overriding their free will
as individuals, directly or indirectly.)
</li>
            <li>DONE - Are project decisions being made in public by the committers?
</li>
            <li>DONE - Are the decision-making guidelines published and agreed to by
all of the committers?
</li>
          </ul>
        </section>
        <section id="Licensing+awareness">
          <title>Licensing awareness
</title>
          <ul>
            <li>DONE - Are all licensing, trademark, credit issues being taken care
of and acknowleged by all committers?
</li>
          </ul>
        </section>
        <section id="Project+Specific">
          <title>Project Specific
</title>
          <p>
            <em>Add project specific tasks here.
</em>
          </p>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section id="Exit">
        <title>Exit
</title>
        <p>
          <em>Things to check for before voting the project out.
</em>
        </p>
        <section id="Organizational+acceptance+of+responsibility+for+the+project">
          <title>Organizational acceptance of responsibility for the project
</title>
          <ul>
            <li>If graduating to an existing PMC, has the PMC voted to accept it?
</li>
            <li>If graduating to a new PMC, has the board voted to accept it?
</li>
          </ul>
        </section>
        <section id="Incubator+sign-off">
          <title>Incubator sign-off
</title>
          <ul>
            <li>Has the Incubator decided that the project has accomplished all of
the above tasks?
</li>
          </ul>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
