<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
You may obtain a copy of the License at

http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
limitations under the License.
-->
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Mailing List Resolutions</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section id="july-2005">
      <title>Resolution Of July 2005</title>
      <p>Reproduced below is
      <a href="http://www.apache.org/foundation/records/minutes/2005/board_minutes_2005_07_28.txt">the
text of the ASF Board resolution that was adopted in July 2005</a> which pertains to mailing lists:
</p>
<blockquote cite='http://www.apache.org/foundation/records/minutes/2005/board_minutes_2005_07_28.txt'>
       <p>WHEREAS, Project Management Committees (PMCs) within
       The Apache Software Foundation are required to conduct their
       normal business on public mailing lists for their project; and
</p>
       <p>WHEREAS, the Foundation provides each PMC with a private list
       called "pmc" for sensitive discussions for which a public
       discussion is prevented by statute or contractual restraints
       on the Foundation; and
</p>
       <p>WHEREAS, mailing list names are standardized to make it easier
       for project oversight and administration; and
</p>
       <p>WHEREAS, volunteers on Foundation projects frequently make the
       mistake of misdirecting public discussion to the "pmc" lists
       because the name implies a group of people rather than a type
       of discussion.
</p>
       <p>NOW, THEREFORE, BE IT RESOLVED, that the Infrastructure
       Committee be and hereby is directed to rename all "pmc" lists
       to private@project and to use the name "private" for all such
       future lists; and let it further be
</p>
       <p>RESOLVED, that all Project Management Committees within The
       Apache Software Foundation shall restrict their communication
       on private mailing lists to issues that cannot be discussed in
       public, such as discussion of pre-disclosure security problems,
       pre-agreement discussions with third parties that require
       confidentiality, discussion of nominees for project or
       Foundation membership, and personal conflicts among project
       personnel. 
</p>
</blockquote>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
