<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
    Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
    you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
    You may obtain a copy of the License at

    http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

    Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
    distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
    WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
    See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
    limitations under the License.
-->

<!DOCTYPE document
[
<!ENTITY root-path   '..'> <!-- The path to the incubator root -->
]>

<document>
    <properties>
        <title>Guide to Successful Graduation</title>
        <atom url="http://mail-archives.apache.org/mod_mbox/incubator-general/?format=atom">general@incubator.apache.org Archives</atom>
    </properties>
    <body>
        <section id="preamble">
            <title>Guide to Successful Graduation</title>
            <section id='TOC'><title>Contents</title><toc/></section>
            <section id="abstract">
                <title>Abstract</title>
                <p>
                    The intent of this document is to help podlings
                    understand the process of
                    graduation and offer some views about how to approach it.
                    It also links to the Incubator
                    <a href="http://incubator.apache.org/incubation/Incubation_Policy.html#Graduating+from+the+Incubator">exit policies</a>.
                    It is not an inflexible standard but represents a
                    consensus condensed from previous discussions on the
                    incubator general list. It also describes some of
                    the first steps that should be taken after
                    graduation.
                </p>
                <p>
                    This is just a guide. Policy is stated 
                    <a href='http://incubator.apache.org/incubation/Incubation_Policy.html'>here</a>.
                </p>        
                <p>
                  Help to improve the system by posting a patch for
                  this document to the incubator section of JIRA or a
                  comment to the <a 
                    href="lists.html#general+at+incubator.apache.org">general</a> list at
                  incubator.
                </p>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section id="introduction">
            <title>What is Graduation?</title>
            <p>
                Graduation is the act of a podling becoming either a
                subproject under an already existing Apache project, or
                becoming a top level Apache project. Graduating is a
                democratic process: in the end, it comes down to a <code><a 
                href='http://www.apache.org/foundation/voting.html'>VOTE</a></code>. Note
                that during your stay in the incubator, you are already busy
                with the process of Graduating: by adopting Apache procedures,
                growing and fostering your community, having (civil) fights
                concerning code style (tabs versus spaces), cutting releases
                and so forth. All these acts have an influence on your
                projects graduation.

            </p>
            <p>

                The road to graduation is pretty clear: depending on whether your
                project wants to become a top level project, or join as a
                subproject under an already existing project the steps are
                fairly simple but do take time and effort. This document
                provides guidelines for making this process run smooth.

            </p>
            <p>
                This document is offered for guidance and education only.
                Actual policy is documented in the <a
                href="../incubation/Incubation_Policy.html">Incubation Policy
                Guide</a> in <a
                href="../incubation/Incubation_Policy.html#Graduating+from+the+Incubator">this</a>
                section. Please post any questions about graduation
                to the <a href="lists.html#general+at+incubator.apache.org">general incubator list</a>.

            </p>
            <section id='subproject-or-top-level'>
                <title>Whether to Graduate to Subproject or to Top Level Project</title>
                <p>
                    Each proposal has a <a
                    href="&root-path;/incubation/Roles_and_Responsibilities.html#Sponsor">Sponsor</a>.
                    The identity of the Sponsor indicates the natural
                    destination. For proposals sponsored by the <a 
                    href="&root-path;/incubation/Roles_and_Responsibilities.html#board">Board</a> or by
                    the <a
                    href="&root-path;/incubation/Roles_and_Responsibilities.html#Incubator+Project+Management+Committee+%28PMC%29">Incubator
                    PMC (IPMC)</a>, this is a top level project. For others,
                    this is as a subproject of the sponsoring project. However, the
                    destination is fixed only on graduation, not entry. Projects
                    grow and evolve during the graduation process. As
                    graduation approaches, this original preference should be
                    reviewed based on where the project is now.

                </p>

                <p>

                    Graduation as a subproject is only possible if the
                    subproject still falls within the scope of the project and
                    requires the consent of the project <a
                    href='http://www.apache.org/foundation/how-it-works.html#structure'>PMC</a>.
                    Graduation as a project requires the formation of the new
                    project by the <a href="&root-path;/incubation/Roles_and_Responsibilities.html#board">Board</a>.

                </p>
                <p>

                    The <a
                    href="&root-path;/incubation/Roles_and_Responsibilities.html#Incubator+Project+Management+Committee+%28PMC%29">IPMC</a>
                    will also express a democratic opinion. For those seeking
                    to graduate to a subproject this <code><a 
                    href='http://www.apache.org/foundation/voting.html'>VOTE</a></code> 
                    is to approve the
                    transfer. For those seeking to graduation as a top level
                    project, this will be a recommendation to the <a 
                    href="&root-path;/incubation/Roles_and_Responsibilities.html#board">Board</a>.
                    Expect IPMC-ers to ask questions about the project
                    including about the choice of destination. This is part of
                    the normal process.

                </p>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section id="requirements">
            <title>Before You Graduate</title>
            <p>

                Before you start thinking about graduation, you need to make 
                sure you are ready and meet the requirements imposed on Apache projects.
                This section will provide a shortlist for podlings to
                determine if they meet the criteria for asking graduation.

            </p>

            <section id='checklist'>
                <title>Graduation Check List</title>
                <p>

                    The following is a short checklist giving an overview, not
                    a substitute for reading the content below.

                </p>
                <ol>
                    <li>Preparations
                        <ul>
                            <li>

                                Complete (and sign off) tasks documented in
                                the <a href='#notes-status'>status file</a>

                            </li>
                            <li>
                                Ensure <a href='#notes-names'>suitable names</a>
                                for project name and product names
                            </li>
                            <li>

                                Demonstrate ability to <a
                                href='#releases'>create Apache releases</a>

                            </li>
                            <li>

                                Demonstrate <a href='#community'>community
                                readiness</a>

                            </li>
                            <li>

                                Ensure <a href="&root-path;/incubation/Roles_and_Responsibilities.html#Mentor">Mentors</a> and <a
                                href="&root-path;/incubation/Roles_and_Responsibilities.html#Incubator+Project+Management+Committee+%28PMC%29">IPMC</a>
                                have no <a href='#notes-issues'>remaining
                                issues</a>

                            </li>
                        </ul>
                    </li>
                    <li>

                        Decide upon <a
                        href='#subproject-or-top-level'>destination</a>

                    </li>
                    <li>

                        Prepare a <a href='#tlp-resolution'>resolution</a>
                        <em>(top level candidates only)</em>.

                    </li>

                    <li>

                        <a href='#subproject-acceptance'>Subproject acceptance
                        <code>VOTE</code></a> by destination Project <em>(subproject
                        candidates only)</em>

                    </li>
                    <li>

                        <a href="&root-path;/incubation/Roles_and_Responsibilities.html#Incubator+Project+Management+Committee+%28PMC%29">Incubator PMC (IPMC)</a>:
                        <ul>
                            <li>

                                For top level candidates, this is a <a
                                href='#ipmc-top-level-recommendation'>recommendation
                                <code>VOTE</code></a>

                            </li>
                            <li>

                                For subproject candidates, this is a <a
                                href='#subproject-graduation'>graduation
                                approval <code>VOTE</code></a>

                            </li>
                        </ul>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Final <a href='#notes-on-hand-over'>hand-over</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>

                        Consider post graduation <a
                        href='#project-first-steps'>tasks</a>

                    </li>
                </ol>
            </section>

            <section id='notes-status'>
                <title>Checking the Status File</title>
                <p>

                    The status file records and summarizes incubation-related
                    information on the podling. The <a
                    href="ppmc.html#Incubator+ASF+Board+Reports">PPMC</a> is
                    responsible for keeping this file current. Before you are
                    able to graduate, all tasks need to be completed.

                </p>
                <p>

                    The status file is a great way of keeping tabs on how your
                    project is doing and what needs to be done to meet the
                    graduation criteria. The <a 
                    href="&root-path;/incubation/Roles_and_Responsibilities.html#Incubator+Project+Management+Committee+%28PMC%29">Incubator PMC</a> 
                    will check this
                    file when they vote on the graduation of your project.
                    Once all tasks are done and the listed criteria met, your
                    project may be ready for graduation.

                </p>
                <p>

                    The status file of the JUDDI project is <a
                    href='http://incubator.apache.org/projects/juddi.html'>one
                    example</a>.

                </p>
            </section>

            <section id='notes-names'>
                <title>Ensure suitable project name and product names</title>
                <p>
                  Please read <a href="http://www.apache.org/foundation/marks/naming.html">detailed documentation here</a>.
                  The "Process for ensuring suitable project and product names" is mandatory for every podling which wants to
                  graduate.
                </p>
            </section>

            <section id='releases'>
                <title>Creating an Apache Release</title>
                <blockquote cite='http://catb.org/esr/writings/cathedral-bazaar/cathedral-bazaar/ar01s04.html'>
                    <p>Release Early, Release Often</p>
                    <div align='right'>
                        <p>
                            <a href='http://catb.org/esr/writings/cathedral-bazaar/cathedral-bazaar/ar01s04.html'>Eric Steven Raymond</a>
                        </p>
                    </div>
                </blockquote>
                <p>

                    Projects need to cut releases. Apache projects need to
                    understand how to cut Apache releases. Therefore it is an
                    important step during your stay in the incubator to
                    demonstrate the ability to create an Apache Release.

                </p>
                <p>

                    Podlings do not need to actually <em>publish</em> a
                    release to demonstrate that they understand how to
                    accomplish such a feat. However, creating a release that
                    is approved by the <a
                    href="&root-path;/incubation/Roles_and_Responsibilities.html#Incubator+Project+Management+Committee+%28PMC%29">
                    incubator project management committee</a> is usually the
                    simplest way to do this.

                </p>
                <p>

                    If you are going to cut a release (which is highly
                    recommended), then please read the <a
                    href="releasemanagement.html">Incubator Release Management
                    Guide</a> for hints, tips and guidelines for cutting a
                    release that will get approved by the <a
                    href="&root-path;/incubation/Roles_and_Responsibilities.html#Incubator+Project+Management+Committee+%28PMC%29">IPMC</a>
                    without problems.

                </p>
            </section>

            <section id="community">
                <title>Creating an Open and Diverse community</title>
                <p>

                    A major criterion for graduation is to have developed an
                    open and diverse <a
                    href="http://www.apache.org/foundation/glossary.html#Meritocracy">meritocratic</a>
                    community. Time has demonstrated that these kinds of
                    communities are more robust and productive than more
                    closed ones.

                </p>
                <p>

                    Apache projects are self-sustaining and self-governing
                    communities. Long term success and health requires that
                    these communities understand how to:

                </p>
                <ul>
                    <li>recruit users, developers, committers and PMCers</li>
                    <li>take responsible collective action</li>
                    <li>disagree in public on technical matters without destroying personal relationships</li>
                    <li>create an open, positive and inclusive atmosphere on the mailing lists</li>
                </ul>
                <p>

                    Graduation tests whether (in the opinion of the <a
                    href="&root-path;/incubation/Roles_and_Responsibilities.html#Incubator+Project+Management+Committee+%28PMC%29">IPMC</a>)
                    a podling has learned enough and is responsible enough to
                    sustain itself as such a community.

                </p>
                <p>

                    Read more on how to successfully build an open and diverse
                    community for your podling in the <a
                    href="community.html">community guide</a>.

                </p>
                <p>

                    As a project grows, it needs to renew itself by accepting
                    new committers. A project needs to learn how it can
                    recruit new developers and committers into the community.
                    Accepting new committers usually increases the diversity
                    of the project. So, this process is very beneficial. <a
                    href="community.html">Community building</a> requires
                    energy which could have been spent on code development but
                    this cost is an important investment for the future of the
                    project.

                </p>
                <p>

                    The openness of the community is not only measured by the
                    number of contributors. Open and respectful discussions on
                    the mailing lists are vital. Ways to resolve technical
                    conflict without destroying personal relationships must be
                    learned. Learning to use mailing lists effectively is very
                    important. If this can be achieved, then you have shown to
                    be a lively, active and successful community. The future
                    looks bright.

                </p>
                <p>

                    The project is considered to have a diverse community when
                    it is not highly dependent on any single contributor
                    (there are at least 3 legally independent committers and
                    there is no single company or entity that is vital to the
                    success of the project). Basically this means that when a
                    project mostly consists of contributors from one company,
                    this is a sign of not being diverse enough. You can
                    mitigate this requirement by admitting more external
                    contributors to your project that have no tie to the
                    single entity.

                </p>
                <p>

                    Growing an open and diverse meritocratic community is not
                    something that just happens: it takes work. Read the <a
                    href="community.html">building a community guide</a> for
                    guidelines, hints and tips on how you can accomplish this
                    for your project.

                </p>
            </section>
            <section id='notes-issues'>
              <title>Other Issues</title>
              <p>
                    The Incubator relies more on people than rules: rather
                    than try to create rules to cover every circumstance,
                    rules are developed and codified as required. People 
                    are trusted to evolve process and policy. This guide
                    can only document the most common issues and it is
                    possible that there are other concerns that may require
                    resolution that are not covered. 
              </p>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section id="process">
            <title>The Graduation Process</title>

            <section id="toplevel">
                <title>Graduating to a Top Level Project</title>

                <p>

                    Top level projects are created by the <a 
                    href="&root-path;/incubation/Roles_and_Responsibilities.html#board">Board</a>. The <a
                    href="&root-path;/incubation/Roles_and_Responsibilities.html#Incubator+Project+Management+Committee+%28PMC%29">Incubator
                    Project Management Committee (IPMC)</a> can therefore only
                    recommend to the Board that the project is ready to
                    graduate to a top level project.

                </p>
                <p>

                    Graduation to a top level project requires:

                    <ul>
                        <li>a charter for your project</li>
                        <li>a positive community graduation <code><a 
                        href='http://www.apache.org/foundation/voting.html'>VOTE</a></code></li>
                        <li>a positive IPMC recommendation <code><a 
                        href='http://www.apache.org/foundation/voting.html'>VOTE</a></code></li>
                        <li>the acceptance of the <a href='#tlp-resolution'>resolution</a> by the Board</li>
                    </ul>

                    This process can take a while, since it typically sparks
                    some discussion inside the community and possibly in the
                    IPMC.

                </p>
                <p>

                    Here's an estimated timeline for the graduation process.
                    It should help you understand when you should start
                    ramping up your community to get timely graduation and
                    make the process smooth.

                </p>

                <map name="GraffleExport">
                    <area shape="rect" coords="13,112,84,155" href="#tlp-community-vote" />
                    <area shape="rect" coords="15,166,511,209" href="#tlp-resolution" />
                    <area shape="rect" coords="12,220,83,263" href="#ipmc-top-level-recommendation" />
                    <area shape="rect" coords="15,273,79,317" href="#top-level-board-proposal" />
                    <area shape="rect" coords="232,330,293,369" href="http://people.apache.org/calendar.html" />
                </map>

                <img border="0" src="graduation-timeline.png"
                usemap="#GraffleExport" alt="Graduation timeline"
                title="Graduation timeline" />

                <p>

                    For each event we scheduled one or two weeks. Even though
                    a <code><a 
                    href='http://www.apache.org/foundation/voting.html'>VOTE</a></code> 
                    is usually limited to 72 hours, you should prepare
                    for discussion and possibly having to cast a revote with a
                    revised proposal.

                </p>

                <section id='tlp-community-vote'>
                    <title>Community Graduation Vote</title>

                    <p>

                        A community needs to be willing to govern itself
                        before it can become a top level project. A good way
                        to demonstrate this is through a free <code><a 
                        href='http://www.apache.org/foundation/voting.html'>VOTE</a></code> (by the
                        community) on the graduation proposal.

                    </p>
                    <p>

                        This <code>VOTE</code> is not a requirement but is recommended. It
                        is unlikely that <a
                        href="&root-path;/incubation/Roles_and_Responsibilities.html#Incubator+Project+Management+Committee+%28PMC%29">IPMC</a>
                        members will vote to approve graduation unless the <a
                        href="&root-path;/incubation/Roles_and_Responsibilities.html#Mentor">Mentors</a>
                        and community positively express their readiness for
                        graduation. It is wise to notify the <a
                        href='lists.html#general+at+incubator.apache.org'>incubator
                        general list</a> that the community vote is starting. Please do not Cc the
                        vote to the general list as that creates confusion, instead you can either:
                        <ul>
                            <li> FWD the [VOTE] e-mail to the general list, or </li>
                            <li> Send a different copy to the general list indicating that a graduation community [VOTE] is in progress </li>
                        </ul>

                    </p>
                </section>

                <section id='tlp-resolution'>
                    <title>Preparing a Charter</title>
                    <p>

                        So, in this case a suitable <a 
                        href="&root-path;/incubation/Roles_and_Responsibilities.html#board">Board</a> resolution should be
                        drawn up by the community advised by the 
                        <a href="&root-path;/incubation/Roles_and_Responsibilities.html#Mentor">Mentors</a>.
                        Committers can access the podling template for
                        resolutions in the <a
                        href="https://svn.apache.org/repos/private/committers/board/templates/podling-tlp-resolution.txt">committers
                        svn repository</a>. Also, resolutions are included in
                        the Board minutes, which are posted publicly <a
                        href='http://www.apache.org/foundation/board/calendar.html'>
                        here </a> . These contain numerous examples. Good
                        examples include:

                        <ul>
                            <li>
                                Harmony (see section <em>E. Establish the Apache Harmony project</em> in the
                                <a href="http://www.apache.org/foundation/records/minutes/2006/board_minutes_2006_10_25.txt">October 2006 Board minutes</a>)
                            </li>
                            <li>
                                OFBiz (see section <em>B. Establish Apache Open for Business Project</em> in the
                                <a href="http://www.apache.org/foundation/records/minutes/2006/board_minutes_2006_12_20.txt">December 2006 Board minutes</a>)
                            </li>
                            <li>
                                Cayenne (see section <em>C. Establish Apache Cayenne Project</em> in the
                                <a href="http://www.apache.org/foundation/records/minutes/2006/board_minutes_2006_12_20.txt">December 2006 Board minutes</a>)
                            </li>
                        </ul>
                    </p>
                    <p>

                        The original proposal and the status document should
                        be consulted when creating this document. Projects
                        evolve over time and some deviation from the original
                        proposal may well prove acceptable. The <a 
                        href="&root-path;/incubation/Roles_and_Responsibilities.html#board">Board</a>
                        resolution is the ultimate definition of the scope of
                        an Apache project. So, it is important that it
                        reflects the vision for the project as it appears on
                        the eve of graduation.

                    </p>
                    <p>

                        A good resolution is neither too narrow nor too broad.
                        If the project's scope is too narrow, then its
                        activities will be unnecessarily constrained. If a
                        project's scope is too broad then it may lack focus
                        and suffer from governance issues.


                    </p>
                    <p>

                        If you read these resolutions you also see that you
                        need to appoint a <a
                        href="http://www.apache.org/foundation/glossary.html#Chair">Chair</a>
                        for your project. It is up to the 
                        <a href='ppmc.html'>PPMC</a> to choose one
                        person to act as the chair after graduation.

                    </p>
                </section>
                <section id='ipmc-top-level-recommendation'>
                    <title>The Recommendation Vote</title>
                    <p>

                        The <a href='#tlp-resolution'>resolution</a> should be proposed on the general
                        <a href="mailto:general@incubator.apache.org">
                        incubator list</a> before a <code><a href='http://www.apache.org/foundation/voting.html'>VOTE</a></code> 
                        is started to allow feedback. Once a consensus has been reached, a <code>VOTE</code>
                        should be started on the same general incubator list by a member of the <a href='ppmc.html'>PPMC</a> proposing
                        that the <a
                        href="&root-path;/incubation/Roles_and_Responsibilities.html#Incubator+Project+Management+Committee+%28PMC%29">IPMC</a>
                        recommends the resolution to the <a 
                        href="&root-path;/incubation/Roles_and_Responsibilities.html#board">Board</a>.

                    </p>
                </section>
                <section id='top-level-board-proposal'>
                    <title>Submission of the Resolution to the Board</title>
                    <p>

                        Top level projects are created by a <a href='#tlp-resolution'>resolution</a> by the
                        <a
                        href="&root-path;/incubation/Roles_and_Responsibilities.html#board">Board</a>.
                        Once the <a href='#tlp-resolution'>resolution</a> has been
                        finalized and consensus reached, it should be
                        submitted to the Board. For inclusion in the agenda
                        for the next meeting, the resolution should be
                        submitted at least 72 hours before that meeting. A
                        calendar for meetings is <a
                        href='http://www.apache.org/foundation/board/calendar.html'>available</a>.

                    </p>
                    <p>

                        Business for the <a 
                        href="&root-path;/incubation/Roles_and_Responsibilities.html#board">Board</a> should be submitted by a post
                        to the <code>board</code> mailing list. Posting from
                        an Apache address is recommended. Mixing public and
                        private lists on a post is not recommended.

                    </p>
                    <p>

                        The <code>board</code> list is private. 
                        The usual <a
                        href='http://www.apache.org/foundation/how-it-works.html#management'>netiquette</a>
                        for Apache private lists should be observed. So, it is
                        recommended that only the podling and <a 
                        href="&root-path;/incubation/Roles_and_Responsibilities.html#Incubator+Project+Management+Committee+%28PMC%29">IPMC</a> 
                        private
                        lists are CC'd (rather than the general incubator
                        list). Please treat responses with appropriate
                        confidentiality.

                    </p>
                    <p>The submission should include:</p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>A clear subject (for example <em>Establish Foo TLP</em>)</li>
                        <li>A brief introduction</li>
                        <li>The name of proposed VP</li>
                        <li>Links to the <code>VOTE</code> threads</li>
                        <li>Summary of the <code>VOTE</code> results</li>
                        <li>The <a href='#tlp-resolution'>resolution</a> text</li>
                    </ul>
                    <p>For example:</p>
<note><pre>
--
From: &lt;you _at_ apache dot org&gt;
To: &lt;board _at_ apache dot org&gt;
CC: &lt;&lt;project&gt;-private _at_ incubator dot apache dot org&gt;
Subject: proposed resolution: establish &lt;project&gt; TLP

Dear Apache Board,

&lt;Project&gt; is ready for graduation out of the incubator. So, please
consider the draft resolution below at your next meeting.

&lt;thank you, best regards, personal note if you wish, etc etc&gt;

&lt;your name&gt;

--
References:

    Home: &lt;project home page&gt;
    Vote by project: &lt;link to vote thread on project list&gt;
    Vote by incubator: &lt;link to vote thread on general list&gt;

Resolution draft:

    &lt;&lt;resolution goes here, 72 characters wide,
     indent with 4 spaces&gt;&gt;

--
&lt;your e-mail sig, if you have one&gt;
</pre></note>
                    <p>

                        Please try to keep the <code>board</code> list traffic low. Do not
                        submit reminders or ask whether messages have been
                        received on the list. <a
                        href='http://www.apache.org/foundation/members.html'>Apache
                        Members</a> have access to the <a href="&root-path;/incubation/Roles_and_Responsibilities.html#board">Board</a> 
                        archives and may
                        observe Board meetings. To follow the progress of a
                        resolution, please ask a friendly Member or <a
                        href='http://www.apache.org/foundation/board/'>Director</a>.

                    </p>
                </section>
            </section>
            <section id="subproject">
                <title>Graduating to a Subproject</title>
                <p>

                    Subprojects are accepted by a Project Management
                    Committee. The <a
                    href="&root-path;/incubation/Roles_and_Responsibilities.html#Incubator+Project+Management+Committee+%28PMC%29">Incubator Project Management Committee</a>
                    needs to approve the graduation of the podling to a
                    subproject.

                </p>

                <section id='sp-community-vote'>
                    <title>Community Graduation Vote</title>

                    <p>

                        A community needs to be willing to govern itself
                        before it can become a top level project. A good way
                        to demonstrate this is through a free 
                        <code><a href='http://www.apache.org/foundation/voting.html'>VOTE</a></code>
                        (by the community) on the graduation proposal.

                    </p>
                    <p>

                        This <code>VOTE</code> is not a requirement but is recommended. It
                        is unlikely that <a
                        href="&root-path;/incubation/Roles_and_Responsibilities.html#Incubator+Project+Management+Committee+%28PMC%29">IPMC</a>
                        members will vote to approve graduation unless the <a
                        href="&root-path;/incubation/Roles_and_Responsibilities.html#Mentor">Mentors</a>
                        and community positively express their readiness for
                        graduation. It is wise to copy the <a
                        href='lists.html#general+at+incubator.apache.org'>incubator
                        general list</a> and the <a
                        href="&root-path;/incubation/Roles_and_Responsibilities.html#Sponsor">sponsoring
                        top level project</a> when the <code>VOTE</code>
                        is proposed.

                    </p>
                </section>

                <section id='subproject-acceptance'>
                    <title>Subproject Acceptance Vote</title>
                    <p>

                         A formal <code><a 
                         href='http://www.apache.org/foundation/voting.html'>VOTE</a></code> 
                         by the Project <a
                         href='http://www.apache.org/foundation/how-it-works.html#structure'>PMC</a>
                         to accept the podling as a subproject is a
                         prerequisite. Sometimes, projects may feel that the
                         podling has grown too big and would be better as a
                         top level project. The Chair of the project is the
                         right contact.

                     </p>
                </section>
                <section id='subproject-graduation'>
                    <title>Graduation Approval Vote</title>
                    <p>

                        To graduate as a subproject, the <a 
                        href="&root-path;/incubation/Roles_and_Responsibilities.html#Mentor">Mentors</a> 
                        should start a <code><a 
                        href='http://www.apache.org/foundation/voting.html'>VOTE</a></code> 
                        thread on the <a
                        href='lists.html#general+at+incubator.apache.org'>general
                        list</a> proposing that the <a
                        href="&root-path;/incubation/Roles_and_Responsibilities.html#Incubator+Project+Management+Committee+%28PMC%29">
                        IPMC</a> signs off the graduation of the podling as a
                        subproject. This <code>VOTE</code>s should only be started once the
                        project has <code>VOTE</code>d to accept the subproject.

                    </p>
                </section>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section id="life-after-graduation">
            <title>Life After Graduation</title>

            <section id='notes-on-hand-over'>
                <title>Handover</title>
                <p>

                    This is the transfer of virtual resources from the care of
                    the <a 
                    href="&root-path;/incubation/Roles_and_Responsibilities.html#Incubator+Project+Management+Committee+%28PMC%29">IPMC</a> 
                    to the care of either the new or existing top
                    level project taking charge of the graduating community.

                </p>

                <section id='existing-project-hand-over'>
                    <title>Graduating as Subproject</title>
                    <p>

                        This is the simple case. The <a
                        href="&root-path;/incubation/Roles_and_Responsibilities.html#Chair+of+the+Incubator+PMC">IPMC
                        Chair</a> and the Chair of the project accepting the
                        graduating community organize the handover between
                        themselves.

                    </p>
                </section>

                <section id='new-project-hand-over'>
                    <title>Graduating as New Top Level Project</title>
                    <p>

                        When graduating to a new project, the process is more
                        complex. Creating a new project requires a <a
                        href='http://www.apache.org/foundation/board/calendar.html'>resolution</a>
                        to be passed by the <a
                        href='http://www.apache.org/foundation/board/'>Board</a>.
                        Usually once this happens, members of the Board will
                        inform the appropriate chairs and <a
                        href='http://www.apache.org/foundation/how-it-works.html#structure'>PMCs</a>.
                        Occasionally, this will be missed: if more than 72
                        hours has passed since the Board meeting, it may be
                        worth someone posting a polite reminder to their
                        favorite director.

                    </p>
                    <p>

                        The 
                        <a href='#tlp-resolution'>resolution</a> will appoint a Chair for the new
                        project. The Chair will also be appointed an <a
                        href='http://www.apache.org/foundation/'>Officer</a>
                        of the Apache Software Foundation. This allows them
                        access to official resources of the foundation as well
                        as granting power to act on behalf of Apache.

                    </p>
                    <p>
                        Once appointed, the new Chair needs to:
                    </p>

                    <ul>

                        <li>Subscribe to the <code>board</code> mailing list</li>
                        <li>Subscribe to the <code>infrastructure</code> mailing list</li>
                        <li>Ensure that they have been added to 
                            <a href='http://people.apache.org/committers-by-project.html#pmc-chairs'
                            >the PMC chairs group (pmc-chairs) in LDAP</a>.
                            The ASF Secretary should do this without any action on the part
                            of the new chair. As with above, if it has not happened within
                            72 hours of the resolution passing, contact the secretary to
                            remind them.
                        </li>
                        <li>Check out the <a href='https://svn.apache.org/repos/private/foundation/officers'><code>foundation/officers</code></a> folder from the private repository.
                            Users with member or pmc-chairs karma can do this.
                        </li>
                        <li>Add yourself to the <code>foundation/officers/affiliations.txt</code> and the <code>foundation/officers/irs-disclosures.txt</code> files with the appropriate information.</li>
                        <li>Add your details to the foundation web site Officer list at
                            <a href="http://www.apache.org/foundation/index.html">http://www.apache.org/foundation/index.html</a>
                            (in SVN at
                            <a href="https://svn.apache.org/repos/asf/infrastructure/site/trunk/content/foundation/"
                            >https://svn.apache.org/repos/asf/infrastructure/site/trunk/content/foundation/</a>)
                        </li>
                        <li>Review appropriate documentation:
                            <ul>
                                <li>
                                    <a href='http://www.apache.org/dev/pmc.html#chair'>PMC Chair Duties</a>
                                </li>
                                <li>
                                    PMC <a href='http://www.apache.org/dev/#pmc'>documentation</a>
                                </li>
                                <li>
                                    Jakarta <a href='http://wiki.apache.org/jakarta/RoleOfChair'>Chair guide</a>
                                </li>
                                <li>
                                    Incubator <a href='http://incubator.apache.org/guides/chair.html'>Chair guide</a>
                                </li>
                                <li>
                                    Reporting <a href='http://www.apache.org/foundation/board/calendar.html'>calendar</a>
                                </li>
                            </ul>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            Work out a reporting schedule with the <a 
                            href="&root-path;/incubation/Roles_and_Responsibilities.html#board">Board</a>. For
                            the first three months after graduation this will
                            be monthly. After that, the project should slot
                            into a quarterly reporting schedule. Now is a good time to remove
                            the project from the Incubator reporting schedule.
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            Work with the <a 
                            href='http://www.apache.org/dev/index.html#infra'>Apache Infrastructure team</a> 
                            to set up the top level project
                            infrastructure. The various infrastructure tasks that are required
                            (see <a href='#transfer'>check list</a>)
                            should be consolidated into a single issue (see <a 
                            href='https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/INFRA-4069'>this</a> 
                            for example). This should be created in the category 
                            <a 
                            href='https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/IssueNavigator.jspa?reset=true&amp;mode=hide&amp;pid=10410&amp;sorter/order=DESC&amp;sorter/field=priority&amp;resolution=-1&amp;component=10858'>TLP Admin</a>.
                        </li>
                        <li>Ensure the PMC is added to the committee-info.txt file at
                            https://svn.apache.org/repos/private/committers/board/committee-info.txt<br/>
                            There are 3 sections which need to be updated; see instructions in the file.
                            You may need to get a member to help with this.
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                    <p>

                        They should then be able to start assembling the new
                        <a
                        href='http://www.apache.org/foundation/how-it-works.html#structure'>PMC</a>.
                        The starting membership is listed in the 
                        <a href='#tlp-resolution'>resolution</a>. However, the Chair of the new project
                        needs to ensure that private list is created and the
                        membership subscribed.

                    </p>
                    <p>Members of the new PMC need to:</p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>Subscribe to the private mailing list for the project</li>
                        <li>Review appropriate documentation:
                            <ul>
                                <li>
                                    Apache <a href='http://www.apache.org/dev/pmc.html'>PMC Guide</a>
                                </li>
                                <li>
                                    Related <a href='http://www.apache.org/dev/#pmc'>documentation</a>
                                </li>
                            </ul>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                    <p>

                        Once all this is in place, resources can start to be
                        handed over to the new project.

                    </p>
                    <p>

                        Please continue to hang around the Incubator and help
                        new podlings have an easier time than you did!

                    </p>
                </section>
            </section>
            <section id='project-first-steps'>
                <title>First Steps Outside the Incubator</title>
                <p>

                    Graduation is the first step in what is hopefully a long road.
                    There are some issues which incubation may not cover.

                </p>

                <section id='transfer'>
                    <title>Transferring Resources</title>
                    <p>

                        When a project graduates, then the infrastructure
                        resources (mailing lists, websites, source, etc.) need to
                        be transferred from the Incubator to a project's new home.

                    </p>
                    <p>
                      Although the below checklist is still generally useful, <b>the
                      infrastructure process has been streamlined</b>, see
                      <a href="http://www.apache.org/dev/infra-contact#requesting-graduation">
                        http://www.apache.org/dev/infra-contact#requesting-graduation
                      </a>.  You might also want to check JIRA checklist tickets for projects that graduated in the last month or two.
                    </p>
                  
                  <p>Checklist:</p>

                    <ol>
                        <li id="records">Update the Incubator status records
                            <ol>
                                <li>
                                  Like the rest of incubation, graduation is a process. Updating your
                                  status records as you progress will enable others to assist.
                                </li>
                                <li>
                                    Update the podling <a
                                    href='#notes-status'>status page</a>.
                                    All sections should now be filled in
                                    including <em>EXIT</em>. Take some
                                    time to read carefully since this page
                                    forms the final public record for
                                    graduation.
                                </li>
                                <li>
                                    Update the Incubator
                                    <a href='http://incubator.apache.org/projects/index.html'>status
                                    page</a> to denote the project as "graduating" when you commence,
                                    then as "graduated" when you are finished.
                                    The notes <a href='#unincubate'>below</a> will assist.
                                </li>
                            </ol>
                        </li>
                        <li id="source">Source
                            <ol>
                                <li>

                                    Post an announcement to the development list
                                    telling everyone that the repository is about
                                    to be moved

                                </li>
                                <li>

                                    Post an announcement containing instructions
                                    for developers describing how to <code>svn
                                    switch</code> their workspaces

                                </li>
                                <li>

                                    Update site, wikis, <code>pom.xml</code> and
                                    other resources to point to the new repository
                                    location.

                                </li>
                            </ol>
                        </li>
                        <li id="web">
                            Websites
                            <ol>
                                <li>Transfer the podling website
                                    <ol>
                                        <li>

                                            Load the website into its new home.
                                            See <a
                                            href="http://www.apache.org/dev/#web">infra
                                            notes</a>.

                                        </li>
                                        <li>

                                            Update the <code>incubator/site-publish/.htaccess</code> entry to
                                            redirect traffic from the old URLs to
                                            the new.  (svn location is at <code>http://svn.apache.org/repos/asf/incubator/public/trunk/content/.htaccess</code>) - 
                                            NOTE: new Top Level Projects will most likely get an automatic redirection of their website from the Incubator hostname
                                            once the TLP's distribution repository is moved by INFRA.

                                        </li>
                                        <li>

                                            Post an announcement to user and
                                            development lists

                                        </li>
                                        <li>

                                            When using Maven: update
                                            <code>pom.xml</code> for the location
                                            of the website, as well as the place
                                            where the site plugin will deploy the
                                            web site (when applicable).

                                        </li>
                                    </ol>
                                </li>
                                <li>
                                  <em>(Top Level Projects Only)</em>
                                  Add Project To
                                  <a href='http://www.apache.org'>
                                    www.apache.org
                                  </a>
                                  <ol>
                                    <li>
                                      Check out
                                      <code>
                                        https://svn.apache.org/repos/asf/infrastructure/site/trunk
                                      </code>
                                    </li>
                                    <li>
                                      Patch
                                      <code>
                                        templates/blocks/projects.mdtext
                                      </code>
                                    </li>
                                    <li>
                                      Commit, and if you have karma then <a href="https://cms.apache.org/www/publish">publish</a> the updated www site
                                    </li>
                                  </ol>
                                </li>
                            </ol>
                        </li>
                        <li id="mail">Mailing lists
                            <ol>
                                <li>

                                    When your mail lists have been moved by infrastructure,
                                    post an announcement to your lists.

                                </li>
                                <li>

                                    When using Maven: update <code>pom.xml</code> for
                                    the new mailing list address(es). Also update any
                                    documents on your website that show how to
                                    subscribe to the lists and/or find archives.

                                </li>
                                <li>
                        
                                    Send notice to any mailing list archivers
                                    that the
                                    address has changed, and possibly the location of
                                    your project (if it is listed there as being part of the
                                    incubator).

                                </li>
                                <li>
                                
                                    Update website: replace links to old archives with 
                                    links to new ones and add new links to historic 
                                    archives from incubation.
                                    
                                </li>
                                
                                <li>
                                    
                                    Check project-private mailing list membership. 
                                    Mentors should be allowed to remain if they wish to
                                    do so. The subscriber list should otherwise match 
                                    that on the resolution. See <a 
                                    href='http://www.apache.org/dev/committers.html#mail-moderate'>
                                    this</a> and the <a href='http://www.ezmlm.org/'>EZMLM</a> 
                                    "Moderator's and Administrator's Manual".
                                    
                                </li>
                                
                                <li>
                                    
                                    Update mail addresses including:
                                  
                                      <ul>
                                        <li>
                                          confluence commit messages (see adminstration documentation)
                                        </li>
                                        
                                        <li>
                                          issue tracking messages (see administration documentation)
                                        </li>
                                      </ul>
                                   The chair should have karma to perform these
                                   tasks. 
                                </li>
                                <li>
                                   Double-check that all of your lists have sufficient active
                                   <a href='http://www.apache.org/dev/committers.html#mailing-list-moderators'>moderators</a>.
                                </li>
                            </ol>
                        </li>
                        <li id="tracker">Issue Tracking
                            <ol>
                                <li>

                                    Check that the issue tracking system used by the
                                    podling reflects the project's new status.

                                </li>
                            </ol>
                        </li>
                        <li id="dist">Distribution mirrors
                            <ol>
                                <li>
                                                                  After you have  a release at your new home
                                           (<code>/dist/${project}/</code> area),
                                           remove any distribution artefacts from your old
                                           <code>/dist/incubator/${project}/</code>
                                           area.
                                           Remember from the mirror guidelines that everything is automatically added to archive.apache.org anyway.
                                </li>
                            </ol>
                        </li>
                    </ol>
                </section>
              <section id='unincubate'>
            <title>Final Revision of Podling Incubation Records</title>
            <p>
              When a project has finished its graduation steps, then the incubator resources
              need to be updated to indicate that the project is no
              longer incubating. Here are a few of the items that need
              to be done:
            </p>
            <ul>
              <li>
                Update the svn
                <code>incubator/trunk/content/projects/${project}.xml</code>
                file to show the project's status.
              </li>
              <li>
                Update the podling summary metadata file,
                i.e. <code>incubator/trunk/content/podlings.xml</code> svn file.
                See the content/podlings.dtd and follow examples of other recent graduates.
                At the beginning of the process, add the "graduating" element.
                When finished the graduation process, then:
                Change the podling status to "graduated"; 
                add the "enddate" attribute to document when the project graduated;
                add the "resolution" element (see other project examples);
                remove the "graduating" element.
              </li>
              <li>
                After your project has finished reporting to the Incubator, then
                remove the "reporting" element from that <code>podlings.xml</code> file.
              </li>
              <li>
                Ensure that other svn resources for your project have moved to
                your new home.
              </li>
              <li>
                Review this whole graduation guide.
              </li>
              <li>
                NOTE: Please edit this guide to add missing steps and clarifications.
              </li>
            </ul>
          </section>
              <section id='new-responsibilities'>
                <title>New Responsibilities</title>
                <section id='oversight'>
                  <title>Oversight</title>
                  <p>
                    During the stay in the Incubator, the
                    <a
                      href="&root-path;/incubation/Roles_and_Responsibilities.html#Incubator+Project+Management+Committee+%28PMC%29">
                      Incubator PMC (IPMC)
                    </a>
                    was responsible to the
                    <a
                      href="&root-path;/incubation/Roles_and_Responsibilities.html#board">
                      Board
                    </a>
                    for oversight. A graduated project must now take
                    responsibility for its own oversight.
                  </p>
                  <p>
                    A project needs to ensure that its code base is
                    clean from an IP perspective. New committers need to
                    recruited, educated and mentored. Quality releases
                    need to be cut. Community spirit needs to be maintained
                    and conflicts resolved positively. Board reports need
                    to be accurate and prompt.
                  </p>
                  <p>
                    Help is still available but the
                    appropriate bodies (infrastructure, community, legal
                    and so on) should now be approached directly.
                  </p>
                </section>
                <section id='security'>
                  <title>Security</title>
                  <p>

                    Each project needs to be able to manage security issues
                    discovered in their code. By their nature, these issues 
                    need to be dealt with in private. These issues may either 
                    be dealt with on a separate security list or on the 
                    private list. Which list is suitable for security issues 
                    should be noted.

                  </p>
                  <p>

                    Volunteers need to be found from the
                    <a
                      href='http://www.apache.org/foundation/how-it-works.html#structure'>
                      PMC
                    </a>
                    to work with the Apache security team and act as
                    first contacts on security matters. The new project 
                    should make contact with the team soon after graduation
                    and not wait for the first issue to be raised.

                  </p>
                  <p>
                  
                    Projects should adopt a positive attitude towards
                    security issues. It is easy to gain a poor reputation
                    by mishandling of these issues. There are many people
                    at Apache with considerable experience in this area
                    so ask first.
                  
                  </p>
                </section>
              </section>
              <section id='final'><title>Stay In Touch</title>
                <p>
                   Passing through the incubation process gives a very 
                   valuable perspective. Please help to improve the process 
                   by guiding new podlings and by developing improved policy
                   and documentation on the <a 
                   href="lists.html#general+at+incubator.apache.org">general</a> list.
                </p>
              </section>
            </section>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>
