<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
	Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
	you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
	You may obtain a copy of the License at

	http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

	Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
	distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
	WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
	See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
	limitations under the License.
-->
<document>
	<properties>
		<title>Guide to Retirement</title>
		<atom url="http://mail-archives.apache.org/mod_mbox/incubator-general/?format=atom">general@incubator.apache.org Archives</atom>
	</properties>
	<body>
		<section id="preamble">
			<title>Guide to Retirement</title>
			<section id="abstract">
				<title>Abstract</title>
				<p>
					The intent of this document is to help Mentors and other
					community members understand retirement, both as a
					concept and a process.
				</p>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section id="introduction">
			<title>What is Retirement?</title>
			<p>
				A retired podling is one which has been closed down on the
				initiative of the PPMC or the IPMC for various reasons.  It is
				no longer developed at the Apache Incubator and does not have
				any other duties.
			</p>
			<p>
				It's important to view this process as being the retirement of
				the podling community, not the code. It should not be implied
				that the code is not for use - just that it has no community.
				So long as the Incubator's copyright requirements are
				fulfilled by the podling prior to retirement, its source code
				will continue to be made available through version control.
			</p>
			<p>
				Retiring a podling is analogous to moving a top-level Apache
				project to the <a href="http://attic.apache.org">Attic</a>,
				but podlings receive a lower level of ongoing support -- for
				example, podling websites are deleted outright rather than
				munged to indicate retired status.
			</p>
		</section>

		<section id="decision">
			<title>Deciding to retire</title>
			<p>
				In the vast majority of cases, a podling decides to retire on
				its own and that decision is later formally ratified by the
				Incubator PMC; very rarely, the IPMC may act unilaterally.
				(This is deliberate mimicry of Board oversight of TLPs -- 
				the language and role titles change but in general the Board
				and the IMPC merely implement the wishes of the community.)
			</p>
			<p>
				Before the IPMC gets involved, a public discussion and
				community vote SHOULD be held on the podling's dev list.  This
				ensures that all podling stakeholders are properly informed and
				have the opportunity to participate in the decision.
			</p>
			<p>
				The final decision to retire the podling takes the form of a
				vote by the IPMC on general@incubator.
			</p>
		</section>

		<section id='steps-to-retirement'>
			<title>Steps to retirement</title>
			<p>
			Once the IPMC vote to retire the podling has closed, a Mentor
			or other volunteer needs to perform the following steps.
			</p>
			<ol>
				<li>
					Update <code>content/podlings.xml</code>:
					<ul>
						<li>Update podling status to "retired".</li>
						<li>Add an "enddate" attribute set to the date that the IPMC vote concluded.</li>
						<li>Remove the "reporting" element.</li>
						<li>Add the "resolution" element. (Follow the example of other recently retired podlings.)</li>
					</ul>
				</li>
				<li>
					Update the podling's status page with a prominent message
					indicating when the podling retired: &lt;p&gt;&lt;span
					class="retired"&gt;The ${podling} podling retired on
					XXXX-XX-XX&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;.
				</li>
				<li>
					Has the copyright checkbox of the podling's incubation
					status page been checked off? If not, try to resolve it.
					If it cannot be resolved, the podling's source code must
					be removed from version control.
				</li>
				<li>
					Delete the podling's dist dir, so that its releases will no
					longer be mirrored:
					<pre>svn remove https://dist.apache.org/repos/dist/release/incubator/${podling}</pre>
					Any incubating releases will still be available via
					<a href="http://archive.apache.org/dist/incubator">archive.apache.org/dist/incubator</a>.
				</li>
				<li>
					Create a file RETIRED.txt at the top-level of each podling
					source repository.  This should contain something like the
					following:<br/>
					<pre>This podling has been retired, please see:<br/>http://incubator.apache.org/projects/index.html#{podling-name}</pre>
				</li>
                <li>
                    If the podling has a DOAP referenced in the
                    <a href="https://svn.apache.org/repos/asf/comdev/projects.apache.org/data/projects.xml">projects.xml</a>
                    file used for generating
                    <a href="http://projects.apache.org">projects.apache.org</a>,
                    remove the entry.
                </li>
				<li>
					Open a "task" INFRA JIRA ticket entitled "Retire the
					${podling} Incubator podling".  Open sub-tickets
					using "Create Sub-Task" as applicable:
					<ul>
						<li>Close ${podling} mailing lists</li>
						<li>(If copyright task completed) Make ${podling} version control read-only</li>
						<li>(If copyright task <strong>not</strong> completed) Remove ${podling} version control</li>
						<li>(If JIRA) Move ${podling} JIRA to "retired" and set read-only</li>
						<li>(If Bugzilla) Close ${podling} Bugzilla</li>
						<li>Make ${podling} wiki read-only</li>
						<li>Turn off ${podling} automatic builds</li>
						<li>Update ${podling} Incubator SVN
							<ul>
								<li>Add entries to asf-mailer.conf and send mail to cvs at incubator.apache.org</li>
								<li>Remove entries from asf-authorizaton - this makes the directory rw to the Incubator PMC.</li>
							</ul>
						</li>
					</ul>
				</li>
				<li>
					After Infra modifies the website SVN permissions, disable
					the podling website by installing an
					<a href="http://svn.apache.org/repos/asf/incubator/ripple/site/.htaccess">.htaccess</a>
					file at the root of the podling website dir which consists
					of only a redirect to the podling status page.
				</li>
				<li>When all steps towards retirement are done, announce completeness on general@incubator.</li>
				<li>Indicate that the podling is closed down in the next board report.</li>
			</ol>
			<p>
				The user accounts of the projects committers do not need
				to be removed.
			</p>
		</section>
	</body>
</document>
